<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Startups &#8211; TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/startups/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 17:41:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Startups &#8211; TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Wag&#8217;s recovery is a bet on you going back to work</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/wags-recovery-is-a-bet-on-you-going-back-to-work/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/wags-recovery-is-a-bet-on-you-going-back-to-work/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 17:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Acme Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Consumer Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Future of Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank Vision Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[special-purpose acquisition company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tenaya capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wag]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2267328</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Remember Wag? The dog-walking app made huge waves back in 2018 when it raised $300 million from SoftBank's Vision Fund. Wag's back in the news thanks to a SPAC deal that will take it public.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Remember Wag? The dog-walking app made huge waves back in 2018 when it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/30/on-demand-dog-walking-app-wag-raises-300-million-from-softbank-vision-fund/">raised $300 million from SoftBank&#8217;s Vision Fund</a>.</p>
<p>Competing with rival <a href="https://www.rover.com/app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rover</a>, Wag&#8217;s service fell out of our minds in the years since its mega-deal. Today, Wag is back in the news thanks to a <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20220202005230/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recently announced SPAC deal</a> that will take the company public.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on TechCrunch+</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>This means we get a look inside the machine.</p>
<p>In basic terms, Wag&#8217;s results detail a company that took blows during the pandemic as folks stayed home, meaning that they needed external dog care less than before. But, with its results ramping up, Wag expects to continue its recovery thanks to workers heading back to the office this year. The office-return dynamics make Wag&#8217;s forward-looking projections very interesting.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img class="alignright wp-image-2220367 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Let&#8217;s hammer through the SPAC deal terms and then look at Wag&#8217;s historical results and what it expects for the future. After all, the return-to-office question will impact a host of companies beyond Wag. From Uber to DoorDash and beyond, a return to more old-fashioned working conditions would rejigger our economy once again.</p>
<h2>The Wag deal</h2>
<p>Wag is merging with CHW Acquisition Corporation. The deal calls Wag a &#8220;vertically integrated technology platform,&#8221; notably. The release also states that capital is being provided as part of the deal by &#8220;current Wag! and CHW investors,&#8221; including &#8220;Battery Ventures, ACME Capital, General Catalyst and Tenaya Capital.&#8221; That, in a nutshell, is why we care about this deal; it&#8217;s a venture-backed company that is still raising venture capital.</p>
<p>In more boring terms, the &#8220;transaction values the combined company at a pro forma enterprise and equity value of approximately $350 million,&#8221; which isn&#8217;t much. Especially given that private capital into Wag to this point is around the same number. The deal, presuming &#8220;no redemptions from the CHW shareholders, [will] deliver approximately $175 million in gross cash proceeds to the combined company.&#8221;</p>
<p>Shares of CHW Acquisition Corporation trended lower last week, but recovered to $9.82 per share today, a slight discount to the usual $10 per share SPAC price that we tend to see pre-combination. Still, the market hasn&#8217;t thrown up its arms at the deal&#8217;s concept since its announcement. Why? In part because Wag&#8217;s numbers are pointing in the right direction.</p>
<h2>A pandemic recovery</h2>
<p>To understand Wag&#8217;s return to growth, we have to discuss its declines. In short, when the pandemic hit, demand for Wag&#8217;s service &#8212; dog walking, pet care, etc. &#8212; fell off a cliff.</p>
<p>Observe:</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/wags-recovery-is-a-bet-on-you-going-back-to-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2267328</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vivid Money, a financial super app, raises $114M at an $886M valuation to expand in Europe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/vivid-money-a-financial-super-app-raises-114m-at-an-886m-valuation-to-expand-in-europe/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/vivid-money-a-financial-super-app-raises-114m-at-an-886m-valuation-to-expand-in-europe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 16:14:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenger bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenger banks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[continental]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greenoaks Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revolut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ribbit Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank Vision Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solarisBank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vivid Money]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2267331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vivid Money, a challenger bank out of Berlin with 500,000 customers, has made a name for itself with a financial one-stop shop &#8220;super app&#8221; that, in addition to basic checking and money management services, also includes stock and cryptocurrency investing. Now, as it gears up to add more services to its platform and expand across [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://vivid.money/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vivid Money</a>, a challenger bank out of Berlin with 500,000 customers, has made a name for itself with a financial one-stop shop &#8220;super app&#8221; that, in addition to basic checking and money management services, also includes stock and cryptocurrency investing. Now, as it gears up to add more services to its platform and expand across all of Europe, the startup has raised €100 million ($114 million), in a round of funding led by Greenoaks Capital, with Ribbit Capital and new backer SoftBank Vision Fund 2 also participating.</p>
<p>The funding values Vivd at €775 million ($886 milion at today&#8217;s rates). For some context, this is more than double the company&#8217;s valuation (€360 million) when it last raised money, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/vivid-money-raises-73-million-to-build-a-european-financial-super-app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">€60 million round in April 2021</a>. Its user base also increased five-fold in that period, and its revenues grew 25x, the company said. Vivid doesn&#8217;t share the total amount deposited on its platform, or any details about transaction volumes, but Alexander Emeshev, Vivid&#8217;s co-founder, said it is on target to reach 1 million users by the end of this year.</p>
<p>Vivid today is active in four markets &#8212; Germany, France, Spain and Italy &#8212; and the plan will be to add five more this year, and to be available across all of Europe by the end of 2023. In terms of new products, the company is in the early stages of rolling out <a href="https://vivid.money/en-eu/insurance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">insurance offerings</a>, and Emeshev said it will be introducing its first credit products later this year (Vivid currently provides a Visa debit card to users).</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2267331" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Launched in 2020, you could call Vivid a &#8220;COVID-native&#8221; startup, with a mobile-first offering striking the right chord with its 30-something users who had not only been already turning away from traditional banking and investment services, but found themselves spending more time at home due to the pandemic and reconsidering how to manage their financial lives.</p>
<p>As with a number of other neo-banks, Vivid&#8217;s basic free banking is built on top of another provider&#8217;s infrastructure &#8212; in its case, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/solarisbank-raises-224m-at-a-1-65b-valuation-to-acquire-contis-and-expand-its-api-based-embedded-banking-tech-in-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Solarisbank</a>, one of the big embedded finance players in the region. It augments this with more customized money management services that it has built itself &#8212; for example, customers can split their money into up to 15 &#8220;pockets&#8221; based on specific purposes; money can be moved between pockets very easily &#8212; and other personalization services.</p>
<p>Alongside those core services, newer waves of financial services involving cryptocurrency and other newer trading formats, like exchange-traded funds (ETFs), were also gaining ground, so this was something that Vivid also set out to tap.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our vision was to target Continental Europe, a huge market for investment and savings,&#8221; said Artem Iamanov, the other co-founder of Vivid Money, in an interview. &#8220;We knew that decentralized finance, and other kinds of alternative investment approaches, were booming, and that they were not really connected to the traditional banking world.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That disconnect was not only in terms of understanding, but also in terms of how to break into newer services when your whole financial life is based in more traditional platforms.</p>
<p>Vivid&#8217;s solution has been to create a set of services for users to easily learn about and subsequently invest in stocks and currencies using their existing fiat accounts. It does this by way of a portal that gives a fairly wide range of options &#8212; for example it currently has 50 cryptocurrencies from which to choose, along with 3,000 stocks and ETFs &#8212; designed to appeal to users who are likely new to the field of decentralized finance and might be trying different things out. (Among those new investment vehicles are also SPACs; Vivid is one of the few platforms that lets ordinary consumers invest in these vehicles in the region.)</p>
<p>&#8220;We saw a huge gap between old and new stuff, and so we saw an opportunity to create a super app to give users access to products that intersect between these two worlds,&#8221; Iamanov said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="olokhu34Cv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/maybe-neobanks-will-break-even-after-all/">Maybe neobanks will break even after all</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Maybe neobanks will break even after all&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/maybe-neobanks-will-break-even-after-all/embed/#?secret=OyaxAMDDsv#?secret=olokhu34Cv" data-secret="olokhu34Cv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Investing on the platform is free, with Vivid making money on exchange rates and other fees, for example when users invest in U.S. stocks. It also has created a subscription tier that it sells as &#8220;<a href="https://vivid.money/en-eu/prime/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prime</a>&#8221; (I wonder how Amazon feels about that), which lets users skip the fees if they pay a flat monthly rate of €9.90.</p>
<p>In a market full of challenger banks &#8212; and some very close Vivid competitors such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/berlins-trade-republic-nabs-900m-led-by-sequoia-at-a-5b-valuation-to-take-its-neo-broker-app-across-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sequoia-backed neobroker Trade Republic</a> &#8212; Vivid&#8217;s backers believe the company&#8217;s traction and all-in, easy approach that appeals to new consumer investors will see the company picking up more users and usage as it expands.</p>
<p class="p4">“In just over a year, Vivid Money has already built one of Europe&#8217;s most beloved consumer banking platforms, allowing users to manage their entire financial lives in a single app. Since we invested last year, we&#8217;ve been thrilled to watch their rapid pace of new product development, which has delighted existing users, attracted new customers, and deepened the platform&#8217;s value proposition,&#8221; said said Patrick Backhouse, partner at Greenoaks, in a statement. &#8220;We think we are still in the first innings of a revolution in consumer banking, and we are delighted to further our partnership with Vivid as they continue to scale.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/vivid-money-a-financial-super-app-raises-114m-at-an-886m-valuation-to-expand-in-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2267331</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wyvern adds $4M in new non-equity funding for its in-demand hyperspectral imaging tech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/wyvern-adds-4m-in-new-non-equity-funding-for-its-in-demand-hyperspectral-imaging-tech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/wyvern-adds-4m-in-new-non-equity-funding-for-its-in-demand-hyperspectral-imaging-tech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 16:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earth observation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sustainable Development Technology Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wyvern]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2267309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Canadian startup Wyvern only just announced a $4.5 million seed round (which itself nearly doubled close to the wire thanks to new commitments) and entry into Y Combinator, and now it&#8217;s revealing that it has landed another $4 million in funding via Canada&#8217;s Sustainable Development Technology (SDTC) program. The SDTC program offers startups at seed, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Canadian startup Wyvern only just announced a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/space-startup-wyvern-raises-4-5m-and-joins-ycs-latest-cohort/">$4.5 million seed round</a> (which itself nearly doubled close to the wire thanks to new commitments) and entry into Y Combinator, and now it&#8217;s revealing that it has landed another $4 million in funding via Canada&#8217;s Sustainable Development Technology (SDTC) program.</p>
<p>The SDTC program offers startups at seed, growth and scale-up stages funding for projects that can potentially move the needle on clean tech, through partnerships with agencies and companies across public and private sectors. The funding they provide does not require that the startup hand over any equity, nor is it a loan with repayment expectations. Instead, it&#8217;s essentially a contract with measurable outcomes and deliverables set out by the SDTC and its partners, with access to the funding reliant on meeting those goals.</p>
<p>In Wyvern&#8217;s case, SDTC is working with a consortium including cardio digital farming (a BASF subsidiary), Olds College, SkyWatch, MetaSpectral and Wild + Pine. It outlines a three-year project that involves testing Wyvern&#8217;s hyperspectral, satellite-based imaging using Olds College&#8217;s 2,800 acre &#8220;smart farm&#8221; facility.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2267309" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Being flush with cash is incredibly important for Wyvern right now, as the company is working on actually getting its tech to space: The plan is to launch its first &#8220;DragonEye&#8221; observation satellite this year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wI3U70WBOr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/space-startup-wyvern-raises-4-5m-and-joins-ycs-latest-cohort/">Space startup Wyvern raises $4.5M and joins YC&#8217;s latest cohort</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Space startup Wyvern raises $4.5M and joins YC&#8217;s latest cohort&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/space-startup-wyvern-raises-4-5m-and-joins-ycs-latest-cohort/embed/#?secret=o5PbT1ArFY#?secret=wI3U70WBOr" data-secret="wI3U70WBOr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/wyvern-adds-4m-in-new-non-equity-funding-for-its-in-demand-hyperspectral-imaging-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2267309</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equity Monday: How many times must Spotify step on a rake?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/equity-monday-how-many-times-must-spotify-step-on-a-rake/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/equity-monday-how-many-times-must-spotify-step-on-a-rake/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joe rogan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reliance Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[swing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2267294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, a podcast about the business of startups, where we unpack the numbers and nuance behind the headlines. Every Monday, Grace and Alex scour the news, and record notes on what&#8217;s going on to kick off the week. Today we had a fun mix of news and things that made us [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/3ff1685d-98e3-4e87-a4f0-3c76e15e402a?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Equity</a>, a podcast about the business of startups, where we unpack the numbers and nuance behind the headlines. Every Monday, <a href="https://twitter.com/gracedenhall" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Grace</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/alex" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alex</a> scour the news, and record notes on what&#8217;s going on to kick off the week. Today we had a fun mix of news and things that made us laugh.</p>
<ul>
<li>The <a href="https://www.garbageday.email/p/the-end-of-the-metaverse-hopefully" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Spotify-Rogan situation</a> continued as last week ended, with more episodes of the show coming down. More apologies. And more of Spotify trying to straddle the difference between platform and publisher, while hoping to reap the rewards of both while not fully owning up to the responsibility.</li>
<li>Wag <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20220202005230/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">is going public</a>, and my body is <em>ready.</em></li>
<li>From the funding round front, we had quick notes on Swing, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/06/seoul-based-micromobility-startup-swing-grabs-24m-for-growth-expands-to-japan/">which raised a $24 million Series B</a>, and Reliance Health, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/nigerian-healthtech-startup-reliance-health-raises-40m-led-by-general-atlantic/">which raised a $40 million Series B</a>.</li>
<li>And to close us out, an analogy about Facebook through the lens of Alphabet&#8217;s Other Bets line item.</li>
</ul>
<p>Lots of Equity is coming this week, including our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/31/come-hang-with-us-for-live-recordings-of-techcrunch-podcasts-equity-and-found/">first live show of the year</a>. It&#8217;s free and you can come hang out, watch us flub and ask questions! <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/31/come-hang-with-us-for-live-recordings-of-techcrunch-podcasts-equity-and-found/">See you Thursday</a>!</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2267294" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div>
<div class="article-content">
<div>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>,</i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i> Overcast</i></a><i>,</i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i> Spotify</i></a> <i>and all the casts.</i></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/equity-monday-how-many-times-must-spotify-step-on-a-rake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2267294</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SoftBank, Goldman Sachs mint unicorn in Indian commerce startup ElasticRun</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/softbank-goldman-sachs-mint-unicorn-in-indian-commerce-startup-elasticrun/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/softbank-goldman-sachs-mint-unicorn-in-indian-commerce-startup-elasticrun/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 14:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ElasticRun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2267308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SoftBank Vision Fund 2 has led a $300 million investment in ElasticRun as the Japanese conglomerate doubles down on its commerce bet in the world&#8217;s second largest internet market. Goldman Sachs and existing investor Prosus Ventures also participated in the Pune-headquartered startup&#8217;s Series E round, according to regulatory filings ElasticRun made on Monday. The new [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">SoftBank Vision Fund 2 has led a $300 million investment in ElasticRun as the Japanese conglomerate doubles down on its commerce bet in the world&#8217;s second largest internet market.</p>
<p>Goldman Sachs and existing investor Prosus Ventures also participated in the Pune-headquartered startup&#8217;s Series E round, according to regulatory filings ElasticRun made on Monday. The new round values ElasticRun at $1.5 billion.</p>
<p>TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/softbank-in-talks-to-back-india-elastic-run/">reported</a> early last month that SoftBank and Goldman Sachs were in talks to back ElasticRun.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2267308" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>ElasticRun helps hundreds of thousands of neighborhood stores across hundreds of Indian cities and towns secure inventory from top brands and working capital. It collaborates with e-commerce firms and other big brands to help these stores boost their revenues. The e-commerce firms and brands, in turn, gain access to a large market that has historically proven difficult to penetrate.</p>
<p>The new round, which pushes ElasticRun&#8217;s all-time raise to over $430 million, brings more capital to the startup than it had raised in all its previous funding efforts combined.</p>
<p>ElasticRun has developed a crowdsourced, asset-light logistics network of partners who deliver the services to the neighborhood stores (popularly known as kiranas). Some of the major firms that work with ElasticRun to tap this network include Amazon, Tata Consumer Products, Coca-Cola, PepsiCo and Reliance Retail, India’s largest retail chain.</p>
<p>The startup is the latest in a series of bets SoftBank has made on India&#8217;s commerce market. The firm has also backed Flipkart and social commerce startup Meesho.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ShVdc0TtXb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/14/investors-say-indian-startup-funding-could-get-even-hotter-after-record-q3/">Investors say Indian startup funding could get even hotter after record Q3</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Investors say Indian startup funding could get even hotter after record Q3&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/14/investors-say-indian-startup-funding-could-get-even-hotter-after-record-q3/embed/#?secret=tAIVr69MsO#?secret=ShVdc0TtXb" data-secret="ShVdc0TtXb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/softbank-goldman-sachs-mint-unicorn-in-indian-commerce-startup-elasticrun/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2267308</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Navier wants to &#8216;democratize the waterways&#8217; with leisure boats starting at $300K</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/navier-seed-raise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/navier-seed-raise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 14:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global founders capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Navier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Treble]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2266603</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Look, I&#8217;ll admit that I had to Google how much a boat costs, but any time someone pitches a story saying they are trying to &#8220;democratize&#8221; a recreational activity with a product that starts at $300K, I&#8217;ve got to admit I&#8217;m wondering how much it costs to get a guillotine blade sharpened. My Robespierian misgivings [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Look, I&#8217;ll admit that I had to Google how much a boat costs, but any time someone pitches a story saying they are trying to &#8220;democratize&#8221; a recreational activity with a product that starts at $300K, I&#8217;ve got to admit I&#8217;m wondering how much it costs to get a guillotine blade sharpened. My Robespierian misgivings aside, I&#8217;ve got to give it to the team &#8212; Navier&#8217;s next-gen boats are looking pretty slick. Hydrofoils mean that the vessels zip across the top of the water, and beefy battery packs and electric motors mean that the crafts have some of the longest ranges of any electric craft available &#8212; the company reports 75 nautical miles of range, which is about 690 furlongs, or 86 miles, or 139 km, or thereabouts.</p>
<p>The company announced it just closed a $7.2 million seed raise, co-led by <a href="https://www.globalfounderscapital.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Global Founders Capital</a> and <a href="https://treble.vc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Treble</a>, a new fund run by Daniel Gulati, the former MD of Comcast Ventures. Participants in the funding round include Next View Ventures, Liquid2 Ventures, Soma Capital, Precursor Ventures, as well as some angels.</p>
<p>&#8220;We started in 2020. And our ultimate goal is building a new kind of watercraft that cuts the running cost of a marine vessel by 90%,&#8221; explains Sampriti Bhattacharyya, PhD, co-founder and CEO at Navier. &#8220;By combining hydrofoil electrification, advanced composites and intelligent software, we believe we can cut down the running cost of the vessel by an order of magnitude. This would enable a whole new mode of scalable transportation systems and a waterborne transportation system that was never possible before. Forty-six percent of the world lives in coastal cities, so we believe we have a really big potential market.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2266603" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>When pushed on the &#8220;democratization&#8221; part of the play, the company suggests it isn&#8217;t as much in the purchasing of the boat, but in the operating costs, pointing out that traditional fossil fuel-powered boats are almost 15 times more expensive to operate than a car, and that that&#8217;s the driving force for a lack of adaptation of boating for transportation. Navier suggests that the cost comes from two key areas: fuel and labor. The company plans to reduce fuel costs through electric hydrofoil technology and labor costs by making the boats autonomous.</p>
<p>The first product the company is bringing to market is the Navier 27 &#8212; N27 among friends &#8212; which is aimed at the recreational boat market.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2266621" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/N_2_White_Black_Detail.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2266621" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2266621" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/N_2_White_Black_Detail.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="678" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/N_2_White_Black_Detail.jpg 4928w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/N_2_White_Black_Detail.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/N_2_White_Black_Detail.jpg?resize=300,199 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/N_2_White_Black_Detail.jpg?resize=768,509 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/N_2_White_Black_Detail.jpg?resize=680,450 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/N_2_White_Black_Detail.jpg?resize=1536,1017 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/N_2_White_Black_Detail.jpg?resize=2048,1356 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/N_2_White_Black_Detail.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2266621" class="wp-caption-text">I mean, how cool is this thing? <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Navier</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Recreational boating encompasses a very wide range of activities; fishing, watersports or just enjoying a cruise out with friends. It is a very broad range of on-the-water activities that involve a boat for fun,&#8221; Reo Baird, the company&#8217;s CTO, humors my complete lack of boat knowledge. The recreational vessel is step one &#8212; over time, the company is hoping to leverage the efficiency to build floating robo-taxis. &#8220;E<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">ssentially we are building a platform; a highly efficient watercraft. Our long-term goal is actually to use that same platform for mobility as a robotaxi on the water. This becomes possible by reducing the cost &#8212; including fuel and the labor cost.&#8221; </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;If you can build a boat that can compete in cost, speed and convenience, then essentially you are opening up a whole new mode of transportation,&#8221; explains Bhattacharyya. &#8220;Think of the [San Francisco] Bay Area, for example. At the moment there are 10 terminals and five routes. As soon as you make a boat that can go to smaller marinas, you increase your number of terminals from 10 to 65. All of a sudden, you have 2,000 routes available. That unlocks things: Now, Richmond in the East Bay to San Francisco isn&#8217;t an hour drive, it is literally 15 minutes on the water.&#8221;</p>
<p>The efficiency gains are from three areas of the vessel. The main saving comes from the hydrofoil technology, which means that when the boat is at speed, its hull is lifted out of the water, and the vessel is cruising along on little wings. This means that the motors don&#8217;t have to push as much water out of the way to move at speed, which drastically reduces drag and increases efficiency. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hydrofoil#First_passenger_boats" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The tech has been around in passenger craft</a> since the 1950s or so, and is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EkKxjwtNTCo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">undeniably cool</a>. For recreational boaters, it&#8217;s less common, however; they have traditionally been harder to load onto trailers, they aren&#8217;t great for very shallow waters and in order to get the benefit from the foils, you have to move at quite a clip.</p>
<p>&#8220;We haven&#8217;t published the exact minimum speed for takeoff, but it is somewhere in the range of 15 to 18 miles an hour,&#8221; Baird explains.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2266622" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/team.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2266622" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2266622" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/team.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="810" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/team.jpg 5129w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/team.jpg?resize=150,119 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/team.jpg?resize=300,237 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/team.jpg?resize=768,607 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/team.jpg?resize=680,538 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/team.jpg?resize=1536,1215 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/team.jpg?resize=2048,1620 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/team.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2266622" class="wp-caption-text">The Navier founding team, Reo Baird (CTO) and Sampriti Bhattacharyya (CEO). <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Navier</p></div></p>
<p>The other efficiencies are largely gained from using lightweight composite materials (which makes it easier to lift the boat out of the water when it is foiling along), and some very clever design features that further reduce drag and weight.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have an amazing team &#8212; a bunch of us are from MIT and our lead naval architect is <a href="https://biekerboats.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paul Bieker</a>, who also was responsible for Larry Ellison&#8217;s winning boat in the America&#8217;s Cup,&#8221; says Bhattacharyya, explaining how they are working with the legendary ship-builder to design the N27. “Navier is much more than an electric upgrade. We are fundamentally rethinking the boat as we know it. Hydrofoils deliver a vastly superior ride quality that eliminates sea-sickness since you’re foiling over the waves.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company claims it opened for preorders only about a month and a half ago, and sold out of its first 15 vessels pretty quickly. It says it has several hundred inquiries from interested parties who want to get their paws on one of the cool little boats. The eager customers have some waiting to do, however; the prototype is being built in a shipyard in Maine this year, and the first consumer vessels will roll off the production lines in 2023 some time. Navier plans to build the vessels in the U.S.</p>
<p>Navier partnered with boatbuilder Lyman-Morse to fulfill the first year of production for the Navier 27. The first two hulls of the model are currently under construction at the facility in Maine. The company plans to ramp up production to 400+ units by 2024, and prospective customers can sign up for a waitlist to reserve the 2024 boats via the Navier <a href="https://www.navierboat.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">website</a>.</p>
<p>Not to harp on about the French and their head-rolling antics, but the company is named after <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Claude-Louis_Navier" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Claude-Louis Navier</a>, one half of the duo that came up with the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Navier%E2%80%93Stokes_equations" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Navier-Stokes equation</a>, a crucial piece of maths that makes it possible to make hydro-foiling boats.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/navier-seed-raise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2266603</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dawn Health leverages cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia to help you sleep better</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/dawn-health-leverages-cognitive-behavioral-therapy-for-insomnia-to-help-you-sleep-better/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/dawn-health-leverages-cognitive-behavioral-therapy-for-insomnia-to-help-you-sleep-better/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreas Meistad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aura]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cognitive behavioral therapy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dawn Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eoghan McCabe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insomnia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kevin lin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindred Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meditation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OnDeck’s Runway Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rahul Shivkumar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sleep]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Varun Krishnamurthy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2266238</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The mobile app offers evidence-based therapy integrated with a sleep tracker, access to a sleep coach and personalized daily lesson plans.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As we head full throttle into a new year, the continued state of uncertainty is enough to make anyone have some sleepless nights.</p>
<p>For those whose insomnia has taken over, <a href="https://www.dawn.health/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dawn Health</a>, an insomnia treatment startup, wants to put you back in control over your sleep. The company was founded last year by Rahul Shivkumar, previously a product engineer with Intercom and Microsoft; Andreas Meistad, a cognitive behavioral therapist; and Varun Krishnamurthy, previously a software engineer at Yahoo.</p>
<p>Shivkumar knows about insomnia firsthand — he had horrible sleeping problems and became addicted to medication that was supposed to help after they began to lose effectiveness.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2266238" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>He is not alone: The American Sleep Association estimates that <a href="https://www.therecoveryvillage.com/mental-health/insomnia/insomnia-statistics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">70% of Americans have some kind of sleep disorder</a>. In the workplace, that translates into $2,280 in lost productivity for the average worker each year and a total of <a href="https://aasm.org/insomnia-costing-u-s-workforce-63-2-billion-a-year-in-lost-productivity-study-shows/#:~:text=%E2%80%9CCan%20U.S.%20employers%20afford%20not,study%20co%2Dauthor%20James%20K." target="_blank" rel="noopener">$63.2 billion in lost productivity per year</a>, according to the American Academy of Sleep Medicine.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2266241" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2266241" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2266241" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/TechCrunch-Asset.png" alt="Dawn Health" width="1024" height="662" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/TechCrunch-Asset.png 3762w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/TechCrunch-Asset.png?resize=150,97 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/TechCrunch-Asset.png?resize=300,194 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/TechCrunch-Asset.png?resize=768,496 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/TechCrunch-Asset.png?resize=680,440 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/TechCrunch-Asset.png?resize=1536,993 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/TechCrunch-Asset.png?resize=2048,1324 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/TechCrunch-Asset.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2266241" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Dawn Health</p></div></p>
<p>For Shivkumar, getting off of the sleeping pills took six months. Then he tried all of the usual suspects to get to sleep, like meditation, but found some of the popular apps out there were good for the occasional sleeping problem, but not as effective for clinical insomnia.</p>
<p>That’s when he came across cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) for insomnia, a method of care that guides you to identify the thoughts and behaviors that cause sleeping problems or make them worse, and replace them with habits that lead to going to sleep and staying asleep.</p>
<p>“I went through a 12-week session, and although it cost $300 per session, it was worth it because the ROI is that I sleep well now,” Shivkumar said. “That was the inspiration for starting the company.”</p>
<p>Shivkumar and his team started the company in mid-2020 and have harnessed CBT for insomnia into the Dawn Health app that he dubs “the new standard of care for insomnia treatment.”</p>
<p>The mobile app, which is priced at $60 a month, offers evidence-based therapy, based on Meistad’s work, integrated with a sleep tracker. Users are paired with a sleep coach that is trained by Dawn Health’s therapists and have access to a chat function and personalized daily lesson plans.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Dawn Health has treated over 100 patients so far, including some of the tech scene&#8217;s who’s who, like OpenAI CEO Sam Altman, Twitch co-founder Kevin Lin and Galaxy Digital co-founder Sam Englebardt. Shivkumar said early data shows that 80% of people who went through the program hit a point with their insomnia that they were no longer relying on medication, alcohol or marijuana for help.</p>
<p>Now that the company has users under its belt and an iOS app, it is in growth mode and building clinical evidence from research studies that will be important for continuing the standard of care.</p>
<p>To do that Dawn Health raised $1.8 million in a pre-seed round, led by Kindred Ventures, with OnDeck’s Runway Fund and individual investors including Lin, Segment co-founder Ilya Volodarsky and Intercom co-founder Eoghan McCabe. That growth will also include expanding the team and rolling out new products.</p>
<p>With the popularity of wearables (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/fitness-ring-maker-oura-raises-100m/">Oura Ring</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/zeits-early-warning-wearable-for-sleep-strokes-could-save-hours-and-lives/">Zeit</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/googles-soli-returns-to-track-sleep-on-the-new-nest-hub/">Google’s Nest Hub</a>), other sleep tracking apps (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/extra-crunch-partner-perk-find-peace-of-mind-with-spotify-for-mindfulness-sleep-app-aura/">Aura</a>), and smart mattresses (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/30/eight-sleep-raises-86m-as-its-smart-mattress-and-sleep-fitness-technology-approach-500m-valuation/">Eight Sleep</a>) — many of whom attracted recent venture capital attention — Dawn Health is joining an increasingly crowded space carving out a piece of the <a href="https://www.arizton.com/market-reports/sleep-market-size-analysis" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sleep market</a> that is estimated to reach $137 billion by 2026.</p>
<p>“So much of healthcare costs can be summed up by sleeping badly,” Shivkumar said. “Over the long term, there will be real benefits, especially if we can prevent Alzheimer’s and other disorders that data from companies, like Oura, have put out there. If we can fix this earlier in life or prevent sleeping problems altogether, there will be significant health and cost savings.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JGRFX3YIYb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/extra-crunch-partner-perk-find-peace-of-mind-with-spotify-for-mindfulness-sleep-app-aura/">Extra Crunch Partner Perk: Find peace of mind with &#8216;Spotify for Mindfulness &#038; Sleep&#8217; app Aura</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Extra Crunch Partner Perk: Find peace of mind with &#8216;Spotify for Mindfulness &#038; Sleep&#8217; app Aura&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/extra-crunch-partner-perk-find-peace-of-mind-with-spotify-for-mindfulness-sleep-app-aura/embed/#?secret=IcAQGNvPm4#?secret=JGRFX3YIYb" data-secret="JGRFX3YIYb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/dawn-health-leverages-cognitive-behavioral-therapy-for-insomnia-to-help-you-sleep-better/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2266238</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Koneksa&#8217;s $45 million round could help make at-home clinical trials a reality</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/koneksas-45-million-round-could-help-make-at-home-clinical-trials-a-reality/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/koneksas-45-million-round-could-help-make-at-home-clinical-trials-a-reality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Betuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 13:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AyurMaya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[koneksa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote monitoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telehealth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2266400</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rating symptoms on a numerical scale seems easy, but it can be harder than it appears. How much did it hurt when you stubbed your toe? Was it a two out of 10? A four? How often do you wake up at night? Twice, three times? Regularly? Rarely? These imprecise, self-reported scales can be found [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Rating symptoms on a numerical scale seems easy, but it can be harder than it appears. How much did it hurt when you stubbed your toe? Was it a two out of 10? A four? How often do you wake up at night? Twice, three times? Regularly? Rarely?</p>
<p>These imprecise, self-reported scales can be found throughout medicine, even relating to diseases where the stakes are higher than a bruised toenail. Koneksa, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/koneksa-health" target="_blank" rel="noopener">founded in 2013</a>, is working toward discovering and validating clinical biomarkers. That process begins by looking to turn those analog scales digital &#8212; and improve them in the process.</p>
<p>Koneksa has developed a software suite that works with a variety of devices, from portable spirometers to iPhones and Apple Watches. These devices capture data, from which software gleans clinically useful signals and organizes them for review by drug companies or healthcare providers running clinical trials.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2266400" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>On the back of several studies, and work with clinical trials at over 700 sites, Koneksa is announcing a Series C raise of $45 million. The company has been comparatively frugal so far, raising $4 million in Series A and seed funding, and a $16 million Series B.</p>
<p>This round will be part of a big push to usher in what CMO John Wagner calls an “inflection point” in the digital biomarker world. (Wagner comes to Koneksa after stints at Cynga, Merck, Takeda and Foresite Capital. He also edited the journal Clinical and Translational Science.)</p>
<p>“It’s well known that the more measurements you take, the more accuracy you get, and the more power a clinical trial can have. That makes [the trial] smaller, faster and more efficient,” Wagner told TechCrunch. “I like to think of it as the difference between a still photo and a video. A still photo is great, but a video is able to tell the whole story. That’s how we think of digital biomarkers: they tell the whole story compared to traditional biomarkers.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2266722" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2266722" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2266722" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image003.png" alt="" width="1024" height="642" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image003.png 2528w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image003.png?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image003.png?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image003.png?resize=768,481 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image003.png?resize=680,426 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image003.png?resize=1536,962 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image003.png?resize=2048,1283 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image003.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2266722" class="wp-caption-text">Koneksa&#8217;s tremor assessment tool for Parkinson&#8217;s. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Koneksa</p></div></p>
<p>How does Koneksa go about turning analog scales into digital ones? Parkinson’s offers a clear example. A common, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4545638/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">but imperfect</a>, index used to evaluate Parkinson’s patients is called the Unified Parkinson’s Disease Rating Scale &#8212; it’s a multi-part exam that combines questionnaires about mood, daily life and symptoms, with clinical evaluation, like movement tests.</p>
<p>To quantify a tremor, a physician might ask a patient to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cxHpFWKIfGw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stretch out an arm</a>, and flip their palm upwards and downwards as fast as they can. Meanwhile, the clinician watches for subtle changes in speed or shape of that movement. Koneksa’s approach, instead, has that patient hold their phone, and perform the same motion. The phone’s accelerometer and gyroscope record those changes and transmit data to the company’s platform.</p>
<p>Behind the scenes, the company’s algorithms “score” that tremor, similar to how a physician might assign a score after an exam.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“The potential of these sensors to give is a far more granular and, I use this word carefully, a more objective, reading of a man’s tremor &#8212; there’s tremendous potential in what our technology can do,” CEO Chris Benko told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The idea of revamping analog <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/patient-monitoring-startup-doccla-secures-3-3m-seed-funding-for-virtual-wards-platform/">patient monitoring</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/kiddo-picks-up-16mfor-a-kids-wearable-aimed-at-four-chronic-conditions/">techniques</a> with tech has already attracted lots of companies. Koneksa is certainly playing in that world, but it doesn’t have its sights set on just software. It’s going after proving the whole thesis of digital biomarker reliability &#8212; if not supremacy.</p>
<p>It’s great if a phone can pick up tiny hand movements that a doctor might miss. But do those hand movements actually represent tremors? And, do these digitized tests actually tell doctors anything about how patients will fare later on?</p>
<p>To know the answers to those questions, digital biomarkers need to be clinically validated. Without that validation, such tools are ultimately useless in clinical trials.</p>
<p>“We wanted to focus on gatekeeping problems that are important for getting new therapies to market for patients, and then figure out how to do the scientific validation that shows these technology tools are better or equivalent to what’s out there. We have to do that to the standard of the world’s leading drug companies,” Benko said.</p>
<p>That validation is Koneksa’s current focus. In that regard, the company has been able to show that at-home measures do correlate with tests done in a clinic.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cxHpFWKIfGw?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="https://www.atsjournals.org/doi/abs/10.1164/ajrccm-conference.2018.197.1_MeetingAbstracts.A3934" target="_blank" rel="noopener">One study</a> on 12 asthma patients, for example, showed that readouts from an at-home spirometer were comparable to those done in a clinic. The patients did make some mistakes, noted Benko, but because they were able to perform the test more often, the investigators ended up with far more data to work with.</p>
<p>A typical asthma clinical trial, the study notes, would need to enroll about 100 patients to get a meaningful result. Using the at-home tests, the authors suggest they could get the same results with just 18 people. “That&#8217;s what&#8217;s economically interesting to the drug company,” said Benko. “But for the patients, they&#8217;re simply saying, it&#8217;s more convenient, and it&#8217;s more real world.”</p>
<p>The company has also been able to make a compelling case that in-home patient data may yield clinically meaningful insight. For instance, the company has run one study on 66 patients with head and neck cancer, where they used wearable devices to measure daily step counts.</p>
<p>For every 1,000 steps walked, the study found a 26% reduction in hospitalization risk faced by the patients. However, as Benko noted, it was their activity on the weekends (i.e. movement that patients chose themselves) that revealed this statistic, not the movement schedules they adhered to because of weekday responsibilities.</p>
<p>That <a href="https://meetinglibrary.asco.org/record/200130/abstract" target="_blank" rel="noopener">study</a> was presented at the 2021 American Society of Clinical Oncology meeting, but was not published in a journal.</p>
<p>Still, the ultimate decider of clinical validity, at least when it comes to developing drugs, is the FDA. The next step for Koneksa will be to prove these biomarkers are reliable enough to integrate them into the regulatory decision making process.</p>
<p>“What we&#8217;re teeing up right now are Koneksa-owned or Koneksa-collaboration studies with academics in order to push the envelope on clinical validation,” said Wagner.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2266916" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2266916" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2266916" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image001-1-3.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="551" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image001-1-3.png 1261w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image001-1-3.png?resize=150,121 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image001-1-3.png?resize=300,243 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image001-1-3.png?resize=768,622 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image001-1-3.png?resize=680,551 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image001-1-3.png?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2266916" class="wp-caption-text">Koneksa&#8217;s complete range of measures. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Koneksa</p></div></p>
<p>As for the Series C milestones, Koneksa has two goals.</p>
<p>The first is to add to the evidence that backs up their digital biomarker pipeline. In the past, the company has worked alongside their pharma partners to seek out digital biomarkers and validate them. Getting the validation done ahead of these partnerships will allow Koneksa to get new programs off the ground far faster.</p>
<p>The second piece is a launch of what Benko calls a “self-service” platform. This self-service platform allows new partners to combine data from multiple devices and wearables into the same place, and organize them into a dashboard.</p>
<p>“We recognize that the software&#8217;s ability to integrate that [disparate] device data in a clinical trial setting is unique. There isn&#8217;t another asset like it on the market. And so why should we control it for every possible use? We want to be able to open it up to say: &#8216;hey, we can license this platform to you.’”</p>
<p>Though these two goals are operationally distinct, they do have a similar flavor. Koneksa is looking to turn their digital biomarkers and platform into a turnkey solution.</p>
<p>This round was led by AyurMaya, a fund managed by Matrix Capital Management, with participation from Takeda Ventures and Velosity Capital. Existing investors McKesson Ventures, Merck Global Health Innovation Fund, Novartis (dRx Capital), Spring Mountain Capital and Waterline Ventures also participated in the round.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/koneksas-45-million-round-could-help-make-at-home-clinical-trials-a-reality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2266400</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bumble makes its first acquisition with deal for French Gen Z dating app, Fruitz</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/bumble-makes-its-first-acquisition-with-deal-for-french-gen-z-dating-app-fruitz/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/bumble-makes-its-first-acquisition-with-deal-for-french-gen-z-dating-app-fruitz/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[austin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Badoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[barcelona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[belgium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bumble]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CFO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[down]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moscow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netherlands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[switzerland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whitney wolfe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whitney Wolfe Herd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2266958</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dating app company Bumble, Inc. is making its first acquisition with today&#8217;s news that it&#8217;s adding the fast-growing French dating app Fruitz to its family of applications. Though Bumble, Inc. already has an international footprint as the parent company to Badoo, which is particularly popular in Europe, it sees the addition of Fruitz as a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Dating app company Bumble, Inc. is making its first acquisition with today&#8217;s news that it&#8217;s adding the fast-growing French dating app <a href="https://fruitz.io/">Fruitz</a> to its family of applications. Though Bumble, Inc. already has an international footprint as the <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/bumble-dating-app-company-history-2021-ipo-2020-9">parent company</a> to Badoo, which is particularly popular in Europe, it sees the addition of Fruitz as a way to gain more traction with a younger, Gen Z audience.</p>
<p>Deal terms were not being disclosed.</p>
<p>The quirky app Fruitz takes an unconventional approach to help users find matches, as it assigns a fruit to each particular kind of relationship type, ranging from those who want long-term commitments to those in search of one-night action. This allows users to filter out those who aren&#8217;t on the same page as them. It also prompts users to answer questions that serve ice breakers before messaging their match.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2266958" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Fruitz was co-founded by Julian Kabab (CEO), Fabrice Bascoulergue (CTO), and Arnaud Ruols (CFO) and initially launched in France on Feb. 1, 2017. Kabab said the idea for the app came from his own attempt at using dating apps, where he was matched with someone who had different intentions in terms of what they wanted out of the experience.</p>
<p>&#8220;Expressing what you’re looking for is not easy because we’re fearful of being judged. As a result, no one was being honest with their intentions and everyone was wasting each other’s time,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Empowering people to be honest with their intentions was our first mission.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2266988" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2266988" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2266988" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Screen-Shot-2022-02-04-at-3.45.14-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="359" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Screen-Shot-2022-02-04-at-3.45.14-PM.jpg 1946w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Screen-Shot-2022-02-04-at-3.45.14-PM.jpg?resize=150,79 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Screen-Shot-2022-02-04-at-3.45.14-PM.jpg?resize=300,158 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Screen-Shot-2022-02-04-at-3.45.14-PM.jpg?resize=768,405 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Screen-Shot-2022-02-04-at-3.45.14-PM.jpg?resize=680,359 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Screen-Shot-2022-02-04-at-3.45.14-PM.jpg?resize=1536,810 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Screen-Shot-2022-02-04-at-3.45.14-PM.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2266988" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fruitz</p></div></p>
<p>To date, Fruitz has been downloaded 5.6 million times globally across the App Store and Google Play, according to <a href="https://sensortower.com/">Sensor Tower</a> data. As of Feb. 3, 2022, the app was ranked No. 4 on the iPhone&#8217;s top free charts in the &#8220;Lifestyle&#8221; category in its home market of France.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Like many modern-day dating apps, it offers a swipe-based interface and a freemium experience.</p>
<p>For Bumble, however, the draw was not necessarily in the app&#8217;s unique features but rather its demographic. The company saw how Fruitz had particular reach with Gen Z, a growing audience in the dating app market. The app also was gaining traction in key Western European countries, including France, Belgium, Netherlands, Switzerland, and Spain, in addition to seeing rapid growth in Canada.</p>
<p>&#8220;Fruitz is a brand and leadership team that I’ve been following for years,&#8221; said Bumble founder and CEO Whitney Wolfe Herd, in a statement. &#8220;Julian, Fabrice, and Arnaud are dynamic and brilliant leaders who have built a unique product that has struck a powerful chord with consumers in France and across Europe. By plugging the app into our technology platform, community support, brand and growth marketing, we can accelerate Fruitz’s growth,&#8221; she said. &#8220;The acquisition of Fruitz allows us to expand our product offering for consumers in line with our focus on empowering relationships.&#8221;</p>
<p>Bumble will incorporate Fruitz into its suite of dating apps while also providing it with resources including machine learning technology, marketing, localization, and safety platforms. There&#8217;s no plan to rebrand or wind down Fruitz operations. Instead, the app&#8217;s nine-person team, including all co-founders, will continue to run the app from their home country of France. Combined, Bumble, Inc. &#8212; which now includes Fruitz, Badoo and Bumble &#8212; has over 900 employees with offices in Austin, London, Barcelona, Paris and Moscow.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/bumble-makes-its-first-acquisition-with-deal-for-french-gen-z-dating-app-fruitz/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2266958</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigerian healthtech startup Reliance Health raises $40M led by General Atlantic</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/nigerian-healthtech-startup-reliance-health-raises-40m-led-by-general-atlantic/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/nigerian-healthtech-startup-reliance-health-raises-40m-led-by-general-atlantic/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 08:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Africa Health Holdings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diabetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[general atlantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[helium health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kangpe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lagos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telehealth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vezeeta]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2267165</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There’s no denying the growth of healthtech globally over the past three years thanks to the pandemic. The event has accelerated the use of telemedicine, virtual care, and drug delivery, thus fuelling investor interest in the sector. Investment has also trickled down to Africa, with large checks going into growth-stage startups. Lagos- and Texas-based digital [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s no denying the growth of healthtech globally over the past three years thanks to the pandemic. The event has accelerated the use of telemedicine, virtual care, and drug delivery, thus fuelling investor interest in the sector.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investment has also trickled down to Africa, with large checks going into growth-stage startups. Lagos- and Texas-based digital healthcare provider <a href="https://www.getreliancehealth.com/">Reliance Health</a> is the latest beneficiary and is doing so in grand style, raising $40 million. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Series B round is the largest of its kind in African healthtech.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reports say healthtech in Africa should reach a market value of over US$11 billion by 2025 and Reliance Health is looking to play a pivotal role in the continent reaching that capitalization. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2267165" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company was founded in 2016 by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/femikuti/">Femi Kuti</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/opeyemi-olumekun-bb68b436/">Opeyemi Olumekun</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthew-mayaki-00b8345b/">Matthew Mayaki</a>. It uses an integrated process to provide health insurance and telemedicine via partnerships with hospitals and healthcare facilities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our mission is super simple. I mean, the definition is simple, but the execution is sometimes more difficult than that,” said chief executive Kuti to TechCrunch on a call. “So essentially what we’re trying to do is to use technology to make quality health care accessible and affordable in emerging markets.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kuti’s comments highlight critical issues with healthcare in Nigeria: accessibility and affordability. In Nigeria and some emerging markets, it’s common for people to take healthcare for granted. No metrics are in place to guarantee the optimality of healthcare when used, so people tend to accept whatever healthcare is available. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In terms of pricing, hospitals haven’t found a way to charge patients not necessarily at the cheapest fee possible but using price points the general public can comfortably afford.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reliance Health has bundled both vital concepts so that users can get access to an integrated suite of healthcare products via subscriptions. Some of that healthcare is provided by Reliance Health directly&#8211; through its telemedicine platform, drug delivery system, and two clinics based in Lagos, Nigeria. Others are via third-party provider partners: hospitals, diagnostic centres and pharmaceutical centres.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2015, the three co-founders launched Kangpe, a telemedicine-focused startup in Nigeria with a “doctor in your pocket” slogan. But a year into running the business and realizing how early the market was and the systemic follow-up gaps and processes that existed, they pivoted to Reliance.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Back then, for example, if a patient chats with this doctor and he recommends an x-ray checkup or after that, a surgery, what happens next?” he queried. “We weren’t able to manage all those [end-to-end] processes and that necessitated sort of a soft pivot from the whole telemedicine focus thing to this integrated healthcare provider that we’re doing today.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reliance Health operates business-to-business and business-to-customers models. RelianceHMO is the company’s health insurance plan for both sets of customers where individuals can select monthly, quarterly or yearly health plans ranging from ₦3,500 (~$7.00) to ₦148,500 (~$297.00). </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the other hand, businesses can make subscriptions on behalf of their employees, which Kuti said are slightly cheaper than plans used by retail customers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over 200,000 individuals in total from both models use Reliance Health. But the platform has seen the most stickiness with its business customers. The platform serves 600 of them, including Biersdorf Nivea, Jumia and PwC, while maintaining an attributable intention rate of 99%, said Kuti.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With an app, these customers can chat with a doctor, find healthcare providers near them to visit or get medications from and manage the delivery of their drugs. Based on frequent usage, Kuti said Reliance, for instance, could suggest lifestyle changes if a customer was diagnosed with diabetes and make hospital referrals if a user spent hours on the line at his last visit to the clinic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Essentially, what we try to do is to get guide people to the best option in terms of the care that we can receive,” he said. “And regardless of that option is provided by a third-party partner or us, we are more concerned with how we work with the customer to guide them to the best option when it comes to accessing the healthcare data.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2267245" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2267245" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2267245" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/SIM_8090-1280x854-1.jpg?w=680" alt="Reliance Health" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/SIM_8090-1280x854-1.jpg 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/SIM_8090-1280x854-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/SIM_8090-1280x854-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/SIM_8090-1280x854-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/SIM_8090-1280x854-1.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/SIM_8090-1280x854-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2267245" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Reliance Health</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The six-year-old startup said it has averaged a 3.5x year-over-year revenue growth from 2016. The new round of funding led by General Atlantic will fuel this continued growth. It is the first investment made by the U.S.-based growth equity investor in Africa, adding to the growing list of first-time investors leading growth rounds in the last two years, such as FTX, Avenir, SVB Capital and Fidelity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“General Atlantic is thrilled to announce our first technology investment in Africa in Reliance Health, backing a team focused on improving healthcare quality for millions of patients in Nigeria and abroad,” said Chris Caulkin, the managing director of General Atlantic and head of EMEA Technology in a statement. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We have been consistently impressed by Femi and Ope, who exemplify the entrepreneurialism and innovation we see across the African continent.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other investors involved in the round include Partech, Picus Capital, Tencent Exploration, Africa Healthcare Master Fund, P1 Ventures, Laerdal Million Lives Fund and M3 Inc.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This investment is coming two years after the company’s $6 million Series A in January 2020. Reliance previously raised a $2 million seed round months <a href="https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/reliance-health">post-YC</a> in 2017. Investors in both rounds include Partech, Y Combinator, Golden Palm Investments, Ventures Platform, LoftyInc Capital&#8211; and Tencent and Picus, who have participated in the three rounds totalling $48 million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The chief executive said Reliance Health plans to use a part of the funding to build two more clinic facilities in two Nigerian cities, Abuja and Port Harcourt. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reliance Health also intends to hire talent and scale new product lines, especially for Nigerians in the diaspora. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The healthtech company will expand into new markets. Egypt is top of that list, with Reliance Health already hiring a country manager to launch by mid this year. Kuti adds that the company will enter two or three countries before the year runs out.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After years of government- and donor-backed funding initiatives, venture capital in African healthtech is picking up. In 2020, healthtech startups across the continent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/how-african-startups-raised-investments-in-2020/">raised less than $100 million</a>, but that number increased to $370 million last year, according to reports on the African VC landscape. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the sector still makes up less than 10% of total funding, big rounds over the last two years from startups such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/11/middle-east-healthcare-platform-vezeeta-raises-40m-series-d-led-by-gulf-capital/">Vezeeta</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/06/nigerias-helium-health-raises-10m-series-a-for-africa-expansion/">Helium Health</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/african-genomics-startup-54gene-raises-25m-to-expand-precision-medicine-capabilities/">54gene</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/mpharma-raises-35million-in-round-participated-by-tinder-co-founders-jam-fund-bharti-executive/#:~:text=Bharti%20executive%20%7C%20TechCrunch-,mPharma%20raises%20%2435%20million%20in%20round%20joined%20by%20Tinder,founder's%20JAM%20fund%2C%20Bharti%20executive&amp;text=Ghanaian%20health%20tech%20startup%20mPharma,people%20residing%20in%20the%20region.">mPharma</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/healthcare-startup-africa-health-holdings-lands-18-million-series-a-funding-to-roll-out-tech-enabled-services/">Africa Health Holdings</a> and now Reliance Health mean African healthtech is coming of age buoyed by market drivers such as the pandemic, population size, data analytics, and consumer-centricity.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HqmMoqnEsG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/african-tech-took-center-stage-in-2021/">African tech took center stage in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;African tech took center stage in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/african-tech-took-center-stage-in-2021/embed/#?secret=SFl3Yug31E#?secret=HqmMoqnEsG" data-secret="HqmMoqnEsG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lOCIOM35tP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/mpharma-raises-35million-in-round-participated-by-tinder-co-founders-jam-fund-bharti-executive/">mPharma raises $35 million in round joined by Tinder co-founder’s JAM fund, Bharti executive</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;mPharma raises $35 million in round joined by Tinder co-founder’s JAM fund, Bharti executive&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/mpharma-raises-35million-in-round-participated-by-tinder-co-founders-jam-fund-bharti-executive/embed/#?secret=0h0umOTJx3#?secret=lOCIOM35tP" data-secret="lOCIOM35tP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fODv6ymqeE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/11/middle-east-healthcare-platform-vezeeta-raises-40m-series-d-led-by-gulf-capital/">Middle East healthcare platform Vezeeta raises $40M Series D led by  Gulf Capital</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Middle East healthcare platform Vezeeta raises $40M Series D led by  Gulf Capital&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/11/middle-east-healthcare-platform-vezeeta-raises-40m-series-d-led-by-gulf-capital/embed/#?secret=1tGF7BioCD#?secret=fODv6ymqeE" data-secret="fODv6ymqeE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/07/nigerian-healthtech-startup-reliance-health-raises-40m-led-by-general-atlantic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2267165</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Korean micromobility startup Swing grabs $24M for growth, expands to Japan </title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/06/seoul-based-micromobility-startup-swing-grabs-24m-for-growth-expands-to-japan/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/06/seoul-based-micromobility-startup-swing-grabs-24m-for-growth-expands-to-japan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micromobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Korea startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[swing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white star capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2267063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Swing, a South Korean electric scooter and micromobility startup, announced today it has raised $24 million in a Series B round to spur its growth and expansion to Japan.  The funding was led by White Star Capital, which also invested in Berlin-based Tier Mobility, and included existing backer Hashed, among others. With the fresh capital, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><a href="https://www.swingmobility.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Swing</a>, a South Korean electric scooter and micromobility startup, announced today it has raised $24 million in a Series B round to spur its growth and expansion to Japan. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The funding was led by White Star Capital, which also invested in Berlin-based Tier Mobility, and included existing backer Hashed, among others. With the fresh capital, Swing has raised a total of approximately $33 million (40 billion KRW) since its inception in 2019. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Founder and chief executive officer of Swing San Kim told TechCrunch that the startup will use the proceeds to increase its fleet of micromobility and further penetrate the Japanese market. In 2022, Swing plans to deploy 100,000 e-scooters, e-bikes and e-mopeds that will have a swappable battery that’s interchangeable with each other and install 200 charging stations for its own usage and others as options. Swing currently operates a fleet of 35,000 electric vehicles, including e-scooters and e-mopeds. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2267063" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Apart from its Swing app, the shared micromobility startup recently launched a new app called <a href="https://dayrider.co/pass">Dayrider</a> that enables delivery riders to rent e-mopeds or e-scooters for just one or two days without the hassle of charging.</p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The city of Seoul <a href="https://english.seoul.go.kr/seoul-accelerates-distribution-of-evs-and-installation-of-charging-station/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> in September that it will add 62,000 electric motorcycles, including e-mopeds, and install 200,000 additional electric charging stations by 2025 in an effort to reduce greenhouse gas emissions. Seoul also said it would replace 100% of the 35,000 motorcycles used for delivery services with electric motors. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Swing aims to take the market. According to the company, there is no suitable e-moped model that can meet the required demand in South Korea, no supply chain that can sell, repair or resell and no charging stations that offer services to potential e-mopeds users.  </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">When it comes to operations, Swing has taken a franchise model. Chief operating officer of Swing Jason Shin said Swing, with the franchise model, could expand its fleets faster with smaller capital than its peers. Swing sells its branded fleets to franchisees. Then the franchisees charge and maintain the e-scooters using Swing’s proprietary software. Swing currently has more than 50 franchise partners, Kim said. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">“No one doubted the market potential. The problem was who will win the competition. Rather than pouring investors’ money on the ground, our strategy was to build a strong internal operation team to make sure each scooter makes a positive return, which has worked,” said Shin. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Although Swing has generated net profits since its second year of operations, it could not meet its aimed numbers as expected, Kim said. He added that</span><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> the ridership of new users has dropped in the wake of last year&#8217;s tightened regulation on e-scooters. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">South Korea’s revised rules on e-scooter have hurt e-scooter companies in the country. </span><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Under the amended Road Traffic Act, which came into effect in May 2021, e-scooter riders must be 16 years of age or over, have a valid driver’s license and wear a helmet. If the users fail to follow the new regulations, they will be imposed a fine. The e-scooter users also must use bike paths and park the e-scooters away from people and cars. In July, the city of Seoul announced it would tow illegally parked e-scooters and charge a penalty.</span></p>
<p>More than 20 e-scooter rental companies are currently operating in South Korea, where there is no limit on the number of fleets or companies that can run the business in the sector. <span data-preserver-spaces="true">Industry sources told TechCrunch that consolidation started in the e-scooter industry last year. Berlin-based e-scooter platform Wind Mobility, which entered the South Korean market two years ago, shut down its operation in Seoul last October. </span></p>
<h2><strong>Expansion to Japan</strong></h2>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Last year, the startup set up a subsidiary in Japan, aiming to launch its service in Tokyo in the first half of 2022. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Kim said customers and cities in Japan are optimal for e-scooters, with its high smartphone penetration rate, e-bike usage and huge demand for the last-mile trip due to the distance between stations. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">“Last year, the Japanese government opened the door to legally start e-scooter sharing through proof of concept. As a Seoul-based startup, Swing can lead the micromobility adoption in Japan through our operational excellence and accumulated data in a very similar environment,” Kim said. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">“We are at an exciting point of time with e-scooters in the Japanese market, where the government is conducting proof-of-concept projects to fine-tune its guidelines and regulations ahead of a proper launch. This exciting partnership between White Star Capital and Swing will be extremely beneficial for Japanese stakeholders who would have access to Swing’s technological capabilities as well as operational knowledge they have built over the years in Korea. Last-mile logistics remains a challenge in Japan, and we look forward to helping Swing address these issues and to bring a better mobility experience for users, riders, businesses and the public sector counterpart,&#8221; said Shun Nagao, venture partner of White Star Capital said. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tcqpkPcR22"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/why-micromobility-is-poised-to-come-out-of-the-pandemic-stronger-than-before/">Why micromobility may emerge from the pandemic stronger than before</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why micromobility may emerge from the pandemic stronger than before&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/why-micromobility-is-poised-to-come-out-of-the-pandemic-stronger-than-before/embed/#?secret=QlP4hwWCf1#?secret=tcqpkPcR22" data-secret="tcqpkPcR22" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">“Mobility has been a big focus for us as we’ve been fortunate to partner with leading companies such as Tier Mobility and Finn Auto in Europe. Robust guidelines and regulations developed in close partnership with leading companies set the stage for Europe to embrace tech-native mobility and its positive environmental impact. We see South Korea and Japan closely following this trend and anticipate micromobility to reach a critical inflection point in the next few years,” said Eddie Lee, partner of White Star Capital. “White Star Capital will be working very closely with San and his team to support Swing’s ambitious vision to become a global company through entering Japan and growing its logistics capabilities with the new Dayrider business.” </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Swing has more than 100 employees in South Korea and four people in Japan. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/06/seoul-based-micromobility-startup-swing-grabs-24m-for-growth-expands-to-japan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2267063</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fintech Roundup: Corporate spend just can&#8217;t be a winner-takes-all space</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/06/fintech-roundup-corporate-spend-just-cant-be-a-winner-takes-all/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/06/fintech-roundup-corporate-spend-just-cant-be-a-winner-takes-all/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 15:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate spend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ramp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2267069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to my new weekly fintech focused column. I’ll be publishing this every Sunday, so in between posts, be sure to listen to the Equity podcast and hear Alex Wilhelm, Natasha Mascarenhas and me riff on all things startups! And if you want to have this hit your inbox directly once it turns into a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><i>Welcome to my new weekly fintech focused column. I’ll be publishing this every Sunday, so in between posts, be sure to listen to the </i><a href="https://linktr.ee/Equitypod" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i>Equity podcast</i></a><i> and hear </i><a href="https://twitter.com/alex" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i>Alex Wilhelm</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i>Natasha Mascarenhas</i></a><i> and me riff on all things startups! And if you want to have this hit your inbox directly once it turns into a newsletter (soon!), sign up </i><a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters"><i>here</i></a><i>.</i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The competition between corporate spend management startups is heating up. Here in the U.S., major players include Brex, Ramp, Airbase and now, TripActions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have talked at great length with the founders of Brex and Ramp in the past, as well as the individual in charge of that segment within TripActions. It is becoming increasingly clear to me that this is definitely not a winner-takes-all industry. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2267069" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In January, for example, Ramp co-founder Eric Glyman told me:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> think at times people have sort of bashed us and thought maybe this is a card for tech companies and we have many, but the majority of our customers are not startups, and they&#8217;re not tech companies. One of our large customers is a potato farm that&#8217;s been around since the 1940s and is looking to just modernize and automate a lot of core processes. I have a lot of respect for, and learn a lot, from others in our industry, but it is such a massive space.</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The company also plans to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">expand its offering to include more features. For example, last October it launched <a href="https://ramp.com/blog/announcing-ramp-bill-pay">bill pay</a>.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2267083" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2267083" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2267083 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founders-Eric-Karim-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founders-Eric-Karim-1.jpg 3072w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founders-Eric-Karim-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founders-Eric-Karim-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founders-Eric-Karim-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founders-Eric-Karim-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founders-Eric-Karim-1.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founders-Eric-Karim-1.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founders-Eric-Karim-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2267083" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Ramp co-founders Karim Atiyeh and Eric Glyman</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For its part, Brex </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">started its life focused on providing credit cards aimed mainly at startups and SMBs. It now aims to serve as a “financial operating system” for its customers, starting with a premium SaaS service it launched in 2021. Brex has also broadened the type of customer it serves, with co-CEO and co-founder Henrique Dubugras telling me in January that ​​while it continues to serve startups or e-commerce companies that might be smaller businesses with higher growth, it is now adapting to serve mid-market to larger businesses, which have different financial needs as they grow.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Late last year, I spoke with Michael </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sindicich, general manager of </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">TripActions Liquid (the company’s unit that is focused on general expense management), and he told me the company counts among its customers small SMB companies &#8212; from around the 200 employee range &#8212; to multi-global, large enterprises including some Fortune 500 companies.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He also added: “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think a place where we&#8217;ve focused really heavily is actually on expanding globally so being able to issue in different currencies, to reimburse in a bunch of currencies, to really provide a true global solution.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have not yet personally talked to Airbase’s Thejo Kote, but he did tell my colleague, Alex Wilhelm, last year that his company is focused more on the mid-market customer.  One thing is clear, all of these companies want to offer more than corporate cards, and it&#8217;s probably safe to say they’d all like to expand outside of the U.S.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For some context &#8212; in January, Brex confirmed it </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/brex-confirms-12-3b-valuation-hires-meta-exec-to-serve-as-its-chief-product-officer/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised $300 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> at a $12.3 billion valuation. Ramp has reportedly raised a round that boosted its </span><a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/founders-fund-invests-in-corporate-card-startup-ramp-at-8-billion-valuation" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">valuation to $8 billion</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, according to The Information, although the company declined to comment when I reached out. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Airbase</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/airbase-raises-60m-as-the-corporate-spend-market-segments-matures/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> raised $60 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> last July, and more recently, TripActions (which after the COVID-19 pandemic </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/from-0-in-revenue-to-a-7-25b-valuation-why-tripactions-275m-raise-has-fintech-to-thank/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">expanded</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from being a primarily “corporate travel” startup to also, more broadly, a spend management company) was valued at $7.25 billion in October.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The companies all have similar missions in that they want to help companies &#8212; ranging from startups to mid-market companies to enterprises, depending on which of this group you are talking about &#8212; better manage their corporate spend with virtual cards and/or software.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So you can imagine the excitement that the fintech nerd in me felt this week as I reported about how not one, but two of the aforementioned players were involved in the funding round of a new startup, Pluto, that has emerged in the corporate spend space and is focused on the Middle East. Specifically, Ramp as a company and Airbase founder Thejo Kote backed Pluto in its </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/pluto-lands-funding-from-corporate-spend-giants-to-build-ramp-for-the-middle-east/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$6 million seed round </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">that was led by Global Founders Capital. This is notable in that Ramp and Airbase’s Kote backed a company that could be construed as a competitor &#8212; except that it’s not because none of the aforementioned players operate in the Middle East. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So will Ramp end up buying Pluto like </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/brex-buys-weav-a-universal-api-for-commerce-platforms-for-50m/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brex bought Weav</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the Israeli company it had invested in just months prior? That remains to be seen of course, but you know I’ll be paying close attention.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2267085" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2267085" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2267085 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founding_Team-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founding_Team-1.jpg 4096w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founding_Team-1.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founding_Team-1.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founding_Team-1.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founding_Team-1.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founding_Team-1.jpg?resize=1536,1153 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founding_Team-1.jpg?resize=2048,1537 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Founding_Team-1.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2267085" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Pluto / Pluto co-founders CTO Nayeem Zen, CEO Mo Aziz, CPO Mohammed Ridwan</p></div></p>
<h2><strong>Public state of affairs</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, if you had </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">any</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> doubts about the hot state of fintech, I expect they will be eased when you check out the </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/01/fintech-outperformed-the-market-in-2021-and-its-set-to-do-even-better/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">findings</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that Matrix Partners uncovered in its annually published Fintech Index. In looking at </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the performance of public fintech versus the broader market in 2021, the firm found that its Fintech Index “significantly outperformed major public stock indexes as well as a basket of legacy financial service providers for the fifth year in a row.” As a reminder, the Matrix Fintech Index is a market-cap weighted index that tracks a portfolio of 25 leading public fintech companies. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But not all public financial technology companies are doing so great. Case in point, PayPal &#8212; which could perhaps be viewed as one of the earliest fintechs &#8212; saw its shares last week </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/02/what-this-mornings-25-drop-in-paypal-shares-could-mean-for-startups/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">drop by around 25%</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the morning following the company’s earnings report the night before. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In my humble opinion, PayPal has become less user friendly over the years, and I’ve heard more than one complaint about it not backing up people who got hacked on its platform. It used to be the primary method for peer-to-peer payments. But these days, I hear much more often, “Can I Venmo you?” rather than “Can I PayPal you?” This is interesting, considering PayPal bought Venmo in 2013 and now Venmo seems to be growing more rapidly than PayPal’s core offering. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Further evidence of this, according to </span><a href="https://www.pymnts.com/news/2022/paypal-venmo-volume-gains-29-pct-to-61b-super-app-in-focus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">PYMNTS</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, is that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Venmo’s volume in the fourth quarter was up 29%, to $61 billion; for the year, Venmo volume gained 44%, to $230 billion.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Part of the problem was that many of the gains in users that PayPal saw during the pandemic were not long-term, with a large number of people using the platform once and not returning. Not a great sign.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In other public company news, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Block &#8212; formally known as Square &#8212; this week closed on its $29 billion buy of Afterpay, which we originally reported on </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/square-to-buy-buy-now-pay-later-giant-afterpay-in-29b-deal/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Notably, this means that Square sellers can now offer buy now, pay later to customers through Afterpay.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Funding frenzy</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let’s move away from talk of public fintechs to the funding rounds raised by private ones. There were multiple rounds for fintech companies that we covered this week (and of course some that we could not get to). Here’s a quick summary:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Metronome</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which helps SaaS companies charge on a usage basis using its APIs, </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/01/metronome-raises-30m-to-help-software-companies-shift-to-usage-based-pricing-models/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised a $30 million Series A</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> led by a16z.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Withco</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which sits at the intersection of fintech and proptech with a lease-to-own model for SMBs, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">emerged from stealth with </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/01/withco-closes-on-32m-to-help-smbs-own-and-not-lease-the-buildings-they-occupy/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$32 million in funding</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Canaan, Founders Fund, Initialized and NFX are lead investors.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nigerian investment app Bamboo </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/31/tiger-global-and-greycroft-back-nigerian-investment-app-bamboo-in-15m-round/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised $15 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in a Series A round co-led by Tiger Global and Greycroft, writes TC reporter </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/author/tage-kene-okafor/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tage Kene-Okafor</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></li>
<li><b>Bold</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a technology company working to enable financial access to electronic payments in Colombia, </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/colombias-bold-raises-55m-in-tiger-led-round-to-enable-digital-payments-in-latam/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised $55 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in a Series B funding round led by Tiger Global Management.</span>
<p><div id="attachment_2267087" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2267087" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2267087 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Bold1-1-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Bold1-1-1.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Bold1-1-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Bold1-1-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Bold1-1-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Bold1-1-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Bold1-1-1.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Bold1-1-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2267087" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bold</p></div></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Trace Finance</b>, <span style="font-weight: 400;">a Brazilian fintech startup that aims to enable faster and </span>more streamlined cross-border financing, announced a $4.3 million seed funding round.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Tribal Credit</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a B2B </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">payments and financing platform for emerging markets, raised $60 million in a Series B funding round led by SoftBank Latin America Fund. Coinbase Ventures also joined the financing, which saw participation from existing investors BECO Capital, QED Investors and Rising Tide. Here’s a story from last year when I covered the company’s </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/tribal-credit-which-provides-credit-cards-to-startups-in-emerging-markets-raises-34-3m/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Series A raise</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="http://taxfyle.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b>Taxfyle</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which has been described as an “Uber for taxes,” said it oversubscribed a $20 million Series B financing round led by Fuel Venture Capital and IDC Ventures. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="https://r2capital.substack.com/p/41586d4e-33f8-4a49-aa28-767ee592dffa" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b>R2</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which works to enable payment processors, POS systems and marketplaces to offer financing to small and medium businesses in Latin America, raised $5.9 million in a round led by General Catalyst. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bengaluru-based <strong>Jar </strong></span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/jar-india-fintech-tiger-global/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised $32 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in a Tiger Global-led Series A financing round, just </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">months after securing its seed funding</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The seven-month-old fintech app is helping millions of Indians begin their investment and saving journeys, reports our own </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/author/manish-singh/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Manish Singh</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>New funds</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There was also an emergence of a couple of fintech-related funds. Miguel Armaza and Andrew Endicott raised $9.25 million for their fund, </span><a href="https://www.gilgameshvc.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gilgamesh Ventures</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The early-stage firm is focused on investing in fintech companies in the U.S. and LatAm. Miguel, who is also just a very nice guy,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has become a prominent podcast host via </span><a href="https://fintechleaders.substack.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fintech Leaders</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (which he founded) and the Wharton Fintech Podcast, which he co-hosted from January 2020 to August 2021 and grew 13x to a monthly audience of 130k.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, after spending the last 10 years as a partner investing in New York-based consumer startups at Lerer Hippeau and Collaborative Fund, </span><a href="https://twitter.com/taylorgreene?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Taylor Greene </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">says he has “quietly” raised a $50 million fund for his new firm, </span><a href="https://www.twelvebelow.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Twelve Below</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The fund will back seed-stage founders based in New York City with an emphasis on fintech and healthcare, “offering them the bespoke and individualized partnership they need to go-to-market.” To date, it has invested in </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/13/tiger-global-accrue-savings-save-now-pay-later-purchases/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Accrue Savings</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (seed lead), and three unannounced seed rounds in fintech and healthcare.</span></p>
<h2><strong>CEOs gone wild?</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Better.com was in the news again last week as more top executives parted ways with the digital mortgage lender in the wake of CEO Vishal Garg’s return, just weeks after it was revealed that two board members had resigned from the company. I have the scoop with all sorts of juicy details </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/better-com-loses-more-top-execs/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Also, be sure to check out </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/author/connie-loizos/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Connie Loizos’</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> excellent coverage of the fact that Bolt’s Ryan Breslow is </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/31/ryanbreslow-bolt/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">no longer CEO</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of the fintech company he founded after his “fiery tirades” on Twitter ruffled more than just a few feathers.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AuqvGDFOJG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/how-does-former-better-com-ceo-vishal-garg-still-have-a-job/">How does former Better.com CEO Vishal Garg still have a job?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How does former Better.com CEO Vishal Garg still have a job?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/how-does-former-better-com-ceo-vishal-garg-still-have-a-job/embed/#?secret=q8zjQELzw6#?secret=AuqvGDFOJG" data-secret="AuqvGDFOJG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before I go &#8212; I was honored to be included in Belvo’s </span><a href="https://belvo.com/blog/top-fintech-influencers-and-newsletters-to-follow-in-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">list</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of top fintech influencers and newsletters to follow in 2022. I’ve never before thought of myself as an influencer, but if the term pertains to fintech, I’ll gladly take it &#8212; especially as I am among stellar company on this list.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And that&#8217;s a wrap. I’d like to acknowledge that there were way too many men in this column&#8217;s edition, so more females in fintech to come.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Have a great Sunday and see you next week!</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/06/fintech-roundup-corporate-spend-just-cant-be-a-winner-takes-all/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2267069</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Q5D is using robots to automate electronic wiring during manufacturing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/05/q5d-is-using-robots-to-automate-electronic-wiring-during-manufacturing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/05/q5d-is-using-robots-to-automate-electronic-wiring-during-manufacturing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 22:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chrysalix Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[q5d]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sosv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2267036</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Q5D’s proposition is a simple one: use robotics to automate the process of producing wiring harnesses for electronics. It’s one that &#8212; surprisingly &#8212; is often still executed by hand, owing to its overall complexity. It’s a process, the company is quick to point out, that hasn’t really changed all that much over the previous [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Q5D’s proposition is a simple one: use robotics to automate the process of producing wiring harnesses for electronics. It’s one that &#8212; surprisingly &#8212; is often still executed by hand, owing to its overall complexity. It’s a process, the company is quick to point out, that hasn’t really changed all that much over the previous century. Turning things over to machines would help speed up the process of manufacturing (a definite plus amid all of the current slow downs), lower costs and mitigate human error.</p>
<p>The Bristol, U.K. startup was founded in 2019 by Steve Bennington and Chris Elsworthy, who were previously involved in Cella Energy and CEL-UK and now serve as CEO and CTO, respectively. In fact, the firm is actually a joint venture between CEL-UK &#8212; a company that makes 3D printers (including the Robox brand) &#8212; and M-Solv, which makes machine tools for electronics manufacturing.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2267038" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2267038" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2267038" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Q5D_heads_rear_close-Copy.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Q5D_heads_rear_close-Copy.jpg 5184w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Q5D_heads_rear_close-Copy.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Q5D_heads_rear_close-Copy.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Q5D_heads_rear_close-Copy.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Q5D_heads_rear_close-Copy.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Q5D_heads_rear_close-Copy.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Q5D_heads_rear_close-Copy.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Q5D_heads_rear_close-Copy.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2267038" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Q5D</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2267036" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Q5D is a HAX hardtech startup program alum, with that firm’s parent, SOSV, participating in its newly announced seed round. “Laying wiring inside of products is one of the most manual and tedious parts of manufacturing. Q5D’s process and products are fundamental in closing the loop for automation in advanced manufacturing,” HAX partner Duncan Hunter says in a release tied to the funding.</p>
<p>The $2.7 million seed is led by Chrysalix Venture Capital and features additional participation from the Rainbow Seed Fund. The money will be used to scale up its technology, which is currently being used primarily by aerospace clients, including Safran and Oxford Space Systems. Consumer electronics and automotive are also on the table, though the firm is quick to note that the technology can be deployed across an extremely broad range of categories &#8212; the primary qualifier being electronics that have built-in wiring systems.</p>
<p>“This is a time of great change—the rapid electrification of our transport systems and the increasing function of everything from washing machines to mobile phones means that wiring is becoming more complex and labor intensive,” Bennington says in the release. “The way the world has made wiring for the last 80 years has to change.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/05/q5d-is-using-robots-to-automate-electronic-wiring-during-manufacturing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2267036</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Edtech’s search for the magic metric</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/05/edtechs-search-for-the-magic-metric/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/05/edtechs-search-for-the-magic-metric/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 19:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creator economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future of work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups Weekly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2267043</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to Startups Weekly, a fresh human-first take on this week’s startup news and trends. To get this in your inbox, subscribe here. If there’s one sector that is incessantly in pursuit of Magic Metrics, it’s edtech. For the past two years, I’ve spoken with every top investor and founder in the industry and each [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome to Startups Weekly, a fresh human-first take on this week’s startup news and trends. To get this in your inbox, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">subscribe here.</a></em></p>
<p>If there’s one sector that is incessantly in pursuit of Magic Metrics, it’s edtech. For the past two years, I’ve spoken with every top investor and founder in the industry and each of them have made their own, independent arguments for what is considered an effective outcome in education.</p>
<p>Some argue that completion rates show necessary engagement, while others say that it’s less about how far you get into a course and more about if you show up and participate in the moments that count. Some believe that it’s time to reinvent grading systems, while others think that scores are a way to beat inequity in acceptance rates. The magic metric that does it all &#8212; encompasses outcomes, engagement and heck, even fun &#8212; has always had debate, and honestly, trust issues around it. Still, it’s rare for me to interview someone who will go on the record to say why there’s so much disagreement, or perhaps more interestingly, why they are right and the status quo is wrong.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2267043" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>And that’s why my conversation with Nucamp CEO Ludovic Fourrage stood out to me. Fourrage, who has spent years building up a coding bootcamp with accessible pricing, tells me that he’s no longer publishing job placement metrics in advertising materials. The move was made to rebuild student trust in the industry.</p>
<p>As I wrote in my story, the move is less about Nucamp declaring that it doesn’t market its placement rates, and more indicative of a broader issue: job placement is the most in-demand outcome, but also one of the hardest to deliver. Of course, the obfuscation of metrics can cast a questionable light on a startup. Nucamp doesn’t even share job placement metrics with learners once they join the platform. What it aims to gain in lack of deception, it could lose in lack of transparency. After all, if your job placement rates were so good, why wouldn’t you advertise them?</p>
<p>For my full take on this topic, check out my latest TechCrunch+ column: <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/should-tech-bootcamps-keep-using-job-placement-metrics-in-their-advertising/">Should tech bootcamps keep using job placement metrics in their advertising?</a></strong></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kVjtR8p2bD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/should-tech-bootcamps-keep-using-job-placement-metrics-in-their-advertising/">Should tech bootcamps keep using job placement metrics in their advertising?</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Should tech bootcamps keep using job placement metrics in their advertising?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/should-tech-bootcamps-keep-using-job-placement-metrics-in-their-advertising/embed/#?secret=OAfydQfmOG#?secret=kVjtR8p2bD" data-secret="kVjtR8p2bD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In the rest of this newsletter, we’ll get into Mos’ evolution from an edtech into a fintech, and if your head of product needs a career agent. As always, you can support me by sharing this newsletter, <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">following me on Twitter</a> or <a href="https://natasha.substack.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">subscribing to my personal blog.</a></p>
<h2><strong>Deal of the week </strong></h2>
<p>With $40 million more in funding, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/amira-yahyaoui-wants-mos-to-be-a-radical-fintech-startup/">Mos is evolving</a>. Amira Yahyaoui started the company in 2017 as an edtech business built to help students navigate their way through applying to and attending college. Now, she’s trying to build a “radical” fintech that can support the same user base through all of life’s similarly complicated demands.</p>
<p>When I spoke to Yahyaoui, she talked about how buzzy fintech has gotten &#8212; from NFTs to credit cards with fancy branding. She’s set on building for the masses, even if it doesn’t feel as exclusive and fancy.</p>
<p>“I wish I had to only convince 1,000 nerds,” Yahyaoui said. “But we need to convince 20 million students.”</p>
<p><strong>Here’s why it’s important, per Lux Capital’s Deena Shakir: </strong>“Rather than being a player tangentially on the side of financial access and inclusion, they recognize that they have the unique opportunity to be the primary bank, credit card and home [for] their students,” she said. In other words, the TAM is increasing.</p>
<p><em>Honorable mentions:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/01/metafy-lands-25m-to-scale-its-gaming-coaching-platform/">Metafy combines gaming and coaching </a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/pluto-lands-funding-from-corporate-spend-giants-to-build-ramp-for-the-middle-east/">When Ramp puts money into a Ramp for the Middle East </a></li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_1753376" style="width: 780px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1753376" loading="lazy" class="breakout  wp-image-1753376" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png" alt="" width="770" height="409" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png?resize=768,408 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png?resize=680,361 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png?resize=1536,816 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png?resize=2048,1088 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 770px) 100vw, 770px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1753376" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<h2><strong>Could the Great Resignation force techies to get career agents?</strong></h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/01/free-agent-series-a/">My most read piece this week</a> explored tech’s hot hiring market, and if it’s about time for top tech talent to start hiring career agents. I specifically looked into Free Agency, a startup that recently raised a $10 million Series A, and its marketplace that connects in-demand techies with experienced agents.</p>
<p>Free Agency helped a client secure a senior director of Product role worth more than $900,000 in total compensation, a 53% jump over the client’s previous pay package. In the process, the company arranged 21 interviews with companies like Snapchat, Coinbase and Lyft without requiring the client to send out a single application or email during his job search.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s why it’s important: </strong>As I spoke about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/taxing-crypto-only-makes-it-stronger/">in the latest Equity podcast</a>, we rarely see recruiting companies building for the employee instead of the employer. Free Agency is a bet that people want to pay so they can take a backseat and let a professional navigate their career opportunities for them. To date, the company estimates it has helped candidates set up 4,700 interviews and secure $200,000,000 in negotiated compensation for total salary offers.</p>
<p>What a time to be an engineer at Stripe:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/the-truth-about-management-in-silicon-valley-it-doesnt-exist/">The truth about management in Silicon Valley: It doesn’t exist</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/no-company-no-problem/">No company, no . . . problem?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/how-to-recruit-when-your-software-startup-is-in-stealth-mode/">How to recruit when your software startup is in stealth mode</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/02/3-ways-web3-recruiters-can-improve-their-hiring-game/">3 ways web3 recruiters can improve their hiring game</a></li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_1599427" style="width: 895px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1599427" loading="lazy" class="breakout  wp-image-1599427" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/zelle-scammers.png" alt="" width="885" height="498" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/zelle-scammers.png 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/zelle-scammers.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/zelle-scammers.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/zelle-scammers.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/zelle-scammers.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/zelle-scammers.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/zelle-scammers.png?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/zelle-scammers.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 885px) 100vw, 885px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1599427" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<h2><strong>In the DMs </strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Plexo Capital raises $79.3 million fund: </strong>Founded by former GV partner Lo Toney, Plexo Capital has closed a second investment vehicle of $79.3 million to back early-stage startups and venture capital funds. <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1833926/000183392622000001/xslFormDX01/primary_doc.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Per SEC filings</a>, this is just the first tranche &#8212; Toney is targeting an end close of $100 million for his newest fund.</li>
<li>Also, has anyone had a busier 12 months than Josh Buckley? The startup CEO and investor, who had a stint as Product Hunt’s chief executive,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/hyper-is-a-new-fund-that-offers-300k-checks-and-promises-of-a-media-slingshot-for-founders/"> is on a launching spree with Hyper</a> and Prologue. His latest project? <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_/status/1489378876950482945" target="_blank" rel="noopener">He’s raising a $500 million fund, per SEC filings.</a></li>
<li>Ro began<a href="https://jobs.lever.co/ro/63208431-443e-467e-b513-e95557522ba7" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> hiring for its new male fertility line</a>, which fits into my scoop on its acquisition of Dadi,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/11/ro-is-in-talks-to-acquire-at-home-sperm-storage-startup-dadi/"> an at-home sperm storage startup. </a></li>
<li>OH from a TechCruncher: Microsoft feels like a startup again, right?</li>
<li>OH from an early-stage founder: Tiger just spent millions of dollars to help me recruit employees.</li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_2217162" style="width: 801px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217162" loading="lazy" class="breakout  wp-image-2217162" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/twitter-2021-10-c.jpg" alt="twitter pattern" width="791" height="445" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/twitter-2021-10-c.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/twitter-2021-10-c.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/twitter-2021-10-c.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/twitter-2021-10-c.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/twitter-2021-10-c.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/twitter-2021-10-c.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/twitter-2021-10-c.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/twitter-2021-10-c.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 791px) 100vw, 791px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217162" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<h2><strong>Across the week</strong></h2>
<p><a href="https://linktr.ee/Equitypod" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Equity</a>, the tech news podcast I co-host alongside Alex Wilhelm and Mary Ann Azevedo, is going live! Join us for a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/equity-live/">virtual, live recording of our show this upcoming Thursday, February 10th </a>&#8212; tickets are free, puns will come at the cost of our producers’ sanity. Our bestie pod, Found, is also joining the live circuit,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/found/"> so listen to them endlessly to prepare. </a></p>
<p><em>Seen on TechCrunch</em></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/02/fck-creator-funds-we-need-a-creator-index-fund/">F*ck creator funds, we need a creator index fund</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/31/ryanbreslow-bolt/">Following his fiery Twitter tirades, Bolt founder Ryan Breslow is no longer CEO — and he says it’s his choice</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/29/please-make-a-dumb-car/">Please make a dumb car</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/31/popular-puzzle-game-wordle-is-being-purchased-by-the-new-york-times/">Popular puzzle game Wordle is being purchased by The New York Times</a></p>
<p><em>Seen on TechCrunch+</em></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/why-2022-insurtech-investment-could-surprise-you/">Why 2022 insurtech investment could surprise you</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/as-public-tech-valuations-fall-are-startup-investments-evolving-quickly-enough/">As public tech valuations fall, are startup investments evolving quickly enough?</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/01/despite-bumps-crypto-investment-starts-2022-with-a-roar/">Despite bumps, crypto investment starts 2022 with a roar</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/31/how-to-build-and-maintain-momentum-in-your-fundraising-process/">How to build and maintain momentum in your fundraising process</a></p>
<p>Until next time,</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_" target="_blank" rel="noopener">N</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/05/edtechs-search-for-the-magic-metric/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2267043</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The startup sobriety gambit</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/05/the-startup-sobriety-gambit/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/05/the-startup-sobriety-gambit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 18:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reframe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The TechCrunch Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vinovest]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2266964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter. It’s inspired by the daily TechCrunch+ column where it gets its name. Want it in your inbox every Saturday? Sign up here.  Hello and welcome to the weekend, my friends! Today we&#8217;re sticking to simple fare. The meat and potatoes &#8212; pea protein and gluten-free starches? [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter. It’s inspired by the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/">daily TechCrunch+ column</a> where it gets its name. Want it in your inbox every Saturday? Sign up <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">here</a>. </em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to the weekend, my friends! Today we&#8217;re sticking to simple fare. The meat and potatoes &#8212; pea protein and gluten-free starches? &#8212; of our beat, namely startup activity. So, read on for some news from startups that we think are pretty neat.</p>
<p>Not to beat the personal drum too hard, but I&#8217;ve had my ins and outs with drinking. Ultimately, I gave it up entirely. So when Reframe entered my view the other week, I was curious.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2266964" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The startup offers an app built to help people reduce their alcohol consumption, focused on individuals who are not physically addicted to the drug but do want to reduce their consumption or quit altogether. The market for help with drinking &#8212; really any drug addiction, dependency or issue &#8212; is huge. I know this because I have the enormous privilege of talking to lots of folks who are looking to cut back or stop boozing altogether. The situation is getting worse during the pandemic, I&#8217;d add.</p>
<p>So I was not surprised to learn that Reframe has been on a rapid trajectory of late, raising $1.4 million from Atlanta Ventures before taking part in Y Combinator (Summer 2021 class, when <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/our-favorite-startups-from-ycs-summer-21-demo-day-part-1/">I cited it</a> as one of my favorites). It raised $3.4 million after the accelerator program and recently closed a $12.5 million round. That final funding event took place just as 2021 closed, and was put together at a $100 million post-money valuation.</p>
<p>The startup is clearly onto something. And, thankfully, it was willing to talk about its results in detail.</p>
<p>I spoke with the company&#8217;s CEO, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/vedantpradeep/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vedant Pradeep</a>, who told The Exchange that in the last six months, Reframe has scaled its ARR by a compounding rate of around 79%. Pradeep also said that his company has seen 10.3% compounding <em>weekly</em> growth over the last 12 months. All that has added up to $9.5 million worth of ARR by January 28, a figure that Pradeep updated to $10 million earlier this week by text message.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Even better, the company&#8217;s mix of tools &#8212; CBT, journaling, etc. &#8212; is helping people make real changes to their drinking. Per Pradeep, some 88.63% of its users &#8220;reported meeting their drinking goals&#8221; at the two-month mark. The CEO added that based on his company&#8217;s data, the preceding data point &#8220;represents a [greater than] 50% reduction in their drinking.&#8221;</p>
<p>That&#8217;s huge. Like <em>huge</em>.</p>
<p>Now, I do have some squeamishness about for-profit care for drug-related matters. But I talked through the company&#8217;s pricing model with Pradeep, as well as his policies regarding those without enough money to pay Reframe. At least by my standards, the company is striking a fair balance.</p>
<p>At a time in which it seems that every tech leader, luminary and knave is piling head-first into the crypto space in hopes of a quick buck, Reframe is a reminder that solving real problems is another way to make money. I just wonder why the company&#8217;s most recent valuation didn&#8217;t have another zero in it, given recent startup pricing trends.</p>
<h2>And speaking of alcohol</h2>
<p>Sticking to the boozing theme of today: wine. It&#8217;s a whole thing.</p>
<p>I can tell you that time spent learning about wine is not wasted. Provided you aren&#8217;t in the Reframe customer demographic, wine snobbery is a fun pastime. Knowing how to enjoy a chablis over a robust California cabernet is table-stakes if you like to plop around chairs with friends and slowly intoxicate your cranium.</p>
<p>But not all wine is strictly for drinking. Some of it is actually investment-grade stuff. Which is why <a href="https://www.vinovest.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vinovest</a> is building a platform to let regulars bet on wine price appreciation. It recently released a way for its customers to invest in individual wines. Previously, Vinovest was more focused on its robo-advisor service in the wine investing category. In short, the company is a wager that more folks want access to alternative investing options, fine wine being one that has usually been out of reach.</p>
<p>I bring the Vinovest news up as it appears to be onto something, posting 500% AUM growth in 2021. Per the company and its intrepid spokesperson <a href="https://twitter.com/_williamruben" target="_blank" rel="noopener">William Ruben</a>, Vinovest holds more than 250,000 bottles in user portfolios, which are stored in &#8220;custom-built warehouses across the world.&#8221;</p>
<p>Between the crypto surge, folks buying digital collectibles and more, perhaps wine investing is going to find allocation in more suburban 401(k)s. If that pans out, well, Vinovest&#8217;s market bet could bear &#8212; fermentable &#8212; fruit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/05/the-startup-sobriety-gambit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2266964</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equity Shot: Making sense of the Paypal and Alphabet earnings</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/05/equity-shot-making-sense-of-the-paypal-and-alphabet-earnings/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/05/equity-shot-making-sense-of-the-paypal-and-alphabet-earnings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 15:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2266992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and happy weekend from the Equity crew! We had a busy week, including a Twitter Space with Natasha and Alex taking to the mics to dig into some tasty public-market news. Naturally our show is more startup-focused than public-market centered. But! We can learn a lot from the world of public companies that have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe height="200px" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless src="https://player.simplecast.com/192c07a0-f1f1-4710-b623-b4615c50c43f?dark=false"></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and happy weekend from the Equity crew! We had a busy week, including a Twitter Space with <a href="http://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> taking to the mics to dig into some tasty public-market news. Naturally our show is more startup-focused than public-market centered. But! We can learn a lot from the world of public companies that have a wide footprint inside particular tech niches that matter for younger companies.</p>
<p>So when we digest <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/02/what-this-mornings-25-drop-in-paypal-shares-could-mean-for-startups/">PayPal&#8217;s results and what investors did to its value this week</a>, we are not super interested in PayPal per se, but more what its results can tell us about the fintech world more generally. After all, around a fifth of all venture capital dollars invested last year went to fintech startups. And Alphabet, it has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/02/with-a-22b-run-rate-does-it-matter-if-google-cloud-still-loses-money/">deep ties to the public cloud space</a>, and the advertising market, both places where startups live and play.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2266992" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="L3JKeokmhX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/31/come-hang-with-us-for-live-recordings-of-techcrunch-podcasts-equity-and-found/">Come hang with us for live recordings of TechCrunch podcasts Equity and Found</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Come hang with us for live recordings of TechCrunch podcasts Equity and Found&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/31/come-hang-with-us-for-live-recordings-of-techcrunch-podcasts-equity-and-found/embed/#?secret=SI0SpwIUkn#?secret=L3JKeokmhX" data-secret="L3JKeokmhX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>We do the occasional live taping on Twitter, so make sure you are <a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">following us on the Big Blue Bird App</a>. Hugs! We are back Monday morning!</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div id="tc-target-mid-article-2260334" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div>
<div class="article-content">
<div>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>,</i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i> Spotify</i></a> <i>and all the casts.</i></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/05/equity-shot-making-sense-of-the-paypal-and-alphabet-earnings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2266992</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Shark Tank India host Ashneer Grover tries to get his BharatPe CEO removed from board</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/daily-crunch-shark-tank-india-host-ashneer-grover-tries-to-get-his-bharatpe-co-founder-fired/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/daily-crunch-shark-tank-india-host-ashneer-grover-tries-to-get-his-bharatpe-co-founder-fired/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 23:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artisanal Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ashneer Grover]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suhail Sameer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2266956</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PST, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><!-- Yay, no errors, warnings, or alerts! --></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for Friday, February 4, 2022! The TechCrunch team is getting pretty stoked for our 2022 slate of live and online events. Equity and Found <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/31/come-hang-with-us-for-live-recordings-of-techcrunch-podcasts-equity-and-found/">are hosting live tapings</a> – for which I can confirm that <a href="https://twitter.com/alex/status/1489656848277987328">tech checks are underway</a> – and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/collaborate-with-the-founder-community-at-techcrunch-early-stage-2022/">we’ve got Early Stage coming in short order</a>. It’s going to be, if I may, a party. – <a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-admin/twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2266956" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2><strong>The TechCrunch Top 3</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/cloud-infrastructure-market-soared-to-178b-in-2021-growing-49b-in-one-year/">The public cloud keeps winning</a>: The Big Tech companies with public clouds did well in the recent earnings cycle. Microsoft, Alphabet and Amazon, that’s to say. The latest data on the cloud market makes it plain why – cloud is big business, software-market equity repricings aside. (More <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/02/with-a-22b-run-rate-does-it-matter-if-google-cloud-still-loses-money/">on Google Cloud here</a>, in case you want a dive into the numbers. <a href="https://twitter.com/ron_miller">Ron’s</a> been all over the cloud beat.)</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/on-metas--headwinds-and-adtechs-privacy-reckoning/">Insurtech venture funding soars as insurtech stocks sour</a>: Last year was perhaps the best year ever for fundraising for insurtech startups. It was also a reckoning year for insurtech companies that went public in the last year or so. TechCrunch, in the first of a two-part series, digs into what’s going on and what good news can be found.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/should-tech-bootcamps-keep-using-job-placement-metrics-in-their-advertising/">How to reform coding bootcamps</a>: TechCrunch’s <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha Mascarenhas</a> has a great look at the world of teaching folks to code in rapid fashion. She told me earlier today that “edtech is always in search of a magic metric, one that encompasses outcomes, engagement and, heck, even fun. But in the world of coding bootcamps, which have been scrutinized over lack of efficacy, is it time to ditch the old way of tracking success?” Enjoy!</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Startups/VC</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/numeral-wants-to-turn-bank-accounts-into-microservices/">The latest from France</a>: Fintech upstart Numeral wants to update corporate banking by “using a modern application programming interface” that will allow its customers to connect “directly to bank servers to upload payment files and interact with outdated information systems.” In short, it’s turning discrete banking services into microservices. I dig it.</li>
<li>Been reading more French startup news in the last few quarters? <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/25/venture-capitalists-fell-in-love-with-europe-last-year/">Here’s why</a>. <a href="https://twitter.com/romaindillet">Romain</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/abracarioca">Anna</a> and others have done a great job keeping our eyes on the country.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/artisanal-ventures-closes-62m-fund-takes-connected-capital-approach-to-investment/">Artisanal Ventures raises $62M</a>: Looking to invest in the competitive B2B SaaS startup market, Artisanal Ventures’ first fund is “backed by more than 50 founders and senior executives,” which could provide it with some leverage for its portfolio companies inside major companies. Let’s see if that edge gets it into the right deals.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/marathon-venture-capital-adds-to-its-newest-fund-to-back-greek-founders-around-the-globe/">Another €30M for Marathon Venture Capital</a>: Based in Athens, Marathon just stacked extra chips for its investing activities. The addition to its latest fund comes after the firm first raised €40 million for its second fund’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/greeces-marathon-venture-capital-completes-first-close-for-fund-ii-reaching-47m/">first close</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/ashneer-grover-suhail-sameer-bharatpe/">Drama at BharatPe</a>: The Tiger-backed Indian fintech company is seeing turmoil in its leadership, with co-founder and managing director Ashneer Grover asking its board “for the removal of chief executive Suhail Sameer” from the leadership group at the company. Throw in the tea from Better.com, Bolt and other firms, and 2022 is shaping up to be a year of tech drama. Why? A lot of companies raised a lot of money, and not all of them are going to manage to make it at those prices. So expect to see more of this, not less, as time rolls along.</li>
<li>And to close us off, if you want to know which funding rounds stood out to us this week, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/taxing-crypto-only-makes-it-stronger/">Equity has you covered</a>. We also talked about cute robots!</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>How to organize and execute an effective hybrid sales kickoff event in 2022</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1801927" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1801927" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1801927" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-497747340.jpg" alt="Abstract vector illustration is showing a team using a diagram to visually organize information." width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-497747340.jpg 4778w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-497747340.jpg?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-497747340.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-497747340.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-497747340.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-497747340.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-497747340.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-497747340.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1801927" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/illustration/people-3d-thinking-mind-mapping-royalty-free-illustration/497747340" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DrAfter123 <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>One recent survey of sales and marketing professionals found that only half of respondents said they were likely to attend an event in H1 2022.</p>
<p>Traditionally, companies hold in-person sales kickoffs (SKOs) in January and February to brief sales teams about new products and devise strategies. Today, those convention centers and hotel ballrooms are dark and quiet.</p>
<p>Hybrid events won’t give teams a chance to bond over karaoke, but with a tight agenda and a compelling theme, you can create a virtual or hybrid SKO that people will actually want to attend.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>If you lead a sales team, this post shares strategies for finding a theme that reflects your goals, as well as advice on scheduling and tips on ways to express your company culture.</p>
<p>Even if your team is spread across several time zones, there’s still time to grab a sandwich and network, and Zoom karaoke counts as team-building.</p>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pXXI5Sas4T"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/how-to-organize-and-execute-an-effective-sales-kickoff-in-2022/">How to organize and execute an effective hybrid sales kickoff event in 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to organize and execute an effective hybrid sales kickoff event in 2022&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/how-to-organize-and-execute-an-effective-sales-kickoff-in-2022/embed/#?secret=Dt9sMs5S7u#?secret=pXXI5Sas4T" data-secret="pXXI5Sas4T" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2><strong>Big Tech Inc.</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/spotify-ceo-hints-hifi-tier-delay-is-related-to-licensing-issues/">Why is there no Spotify HiFi</a>? The leading music streaming business in the world has yet to roll out a higher-priced, higher-quality tier to its service. Why? Licensing, it appears. Which is a somewhat strange answer. Spotify is part-owned by labels, and it has huge market clout. Why can’t it get this done?</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/meta-adds-personal-boundaries-to-horizon-worlds-and-venues-to-fight-harassment/">Personal space comes to Meta</a>: This is going to be an odd blurb, but roll with me. Meta, Facebook’s parent company, is rolling out anti-harassment tools to Horizon Worlds and Horizon Venues, its metaverse properties. So, if that applies to you, good news.</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>TechCrunch Experts<br />
</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/daily-crunch-shark-tank-india-host-ashneer-grover-tries-to-get-his-bharatpe-co-founder-fired/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2266956</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Experts Weekly: Microsegmentation, PMF experiments and personalized shopping</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/experts-weekly-microsegmentation-pmf-experiments-and-personalized-shopping/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/experts-weekly-microsegmentation-pmf-experiments-and-personalized-shopping/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Halpern]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 22:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Experts Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Consultants Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wolfpack Digital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2266696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Growth marketing (TechCrunch+) 3 experiments for early-stage founders seeking product-market fit: Elise King, director of Human Ventures&#8217; entrepreneur-in-residence program and member of the firm&#8217;s investment team, spoke with founders and tells us about finding product-market fit. 3 experiments for early-stage founders seeking product-market fit Tackling touchpoints on your customer’s path to purchase: Returning contributor Jonathan [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Growth marketing</h2>
<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/28/3-experiments-for-early-stage-founders-seeking-product-market-fit/">(TechCrunch+) 3 experiments for early-stage founders seeking product-market fit: </a>Elise King, director of Human Ventures&#8217; entrepreneur-in-residence program and member of the firm&#8217;s investment team, spoke with founders and tells us about finding product-market fit.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xrXIRPu6NQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/28/3-experiments-for-early-stage-founders-seeking-product-market-fit/">3 experiments for early-stage founders seeking product-market fit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 experiments for early-stage founders seeking product-market fit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/28/3-experiments-for-early-stage-founders-seeking-product-market-fit/embed/#?secret=81bDrBupw2#?secret=xrXIRPu6NQ" data-secret="xrXIRPu6NQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/tackling-touchpoints-on-your-customers-path-to-purchase/">Tackling touchpoints on your customer’s path to purchase:</a> Returning contributor Jonathan Martinez shares his thoughts about using segmentation and retargeting to boost conversions:</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2266696" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<blockquote><p>There are myriad resources that can help you extract valuable insights and knowledge. One of my favorites is the Facebook Ad Library, which is a repository of all the platform’s ads that are currently live. This library not only provides you with competitor intel — it also has valuable intel about others in the same verticals or brands who are simply running a great performance marketing program. Another gold mine is an email repository called Really Good Emails.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="e2RsLFMMvd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/tackling-touchpoints-on-your-customers-path-to-purchase/">Tackling touchpoints on your customer&#8217;s path to purchase</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tackling touchpoints on your customer&#8217;s path to purchase&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/tackling-touchpoints-on-your-customers-path-to-purchase/embed/#?secret=uJBwedKRX6#?secret=e2RsLFMMvd" data-secret="e2RsLFMMvd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/11-ways-to-make-personalized-shopping-more-effective-and-profitable/">(TechCrunch+) 11 ways to make personalized shopping more effective and profitable:</a> E-commerce platforms should use every signal they can detect to triangulate shoppers along the customer journey, writes Vitaly Alexandrov, founder and CEO of Food Rocket.</p>
<p>Alexandrov takes us on a deep dive of the online shopping space, sharing marketing tactics and data insights that make mundane shopping experiences more memorable.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“There is no longer a question of whether or not you should offer personalized digital experiences. Anything less is a death knell to your brand’s long-term success.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bcMQSsXqyy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/11-ways-to-make-personalized-shopping-more-effective-and-profitable/">11 ways to make personalized shopping more effective and profitable</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;11 ways to make personalized shopping more effective and profitable&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/11-ways-to-make-personalized-shopping-more-effective-and-profitable/embed/#?secret=bLGtTd2GMF#?secret=bcMQSsXqyy" data-secret="bcMQSsXqyy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="mce-object" style="width: 100%; height: 400px;" title="&lt;script&gt;" data-tf-widget="bwwIWF03" img="" data-wp-preserve="%3Cscript%20src%3D%22%2F%2Fembed.typeform.com%2Fnext%2Fembed.js%22%3E%3Cp%3E%3Cspan%20data-mce-type%3D%22bookmark%22%20style%3D%22display%3A%20inline-block%3B%20width%3A%200px%3B%20overflow%3A%20hidden%3B%20line-height%3A%200%3B%22%20class%3D%22mce_SELRES_start%22%3E%EF%BB%BF%3C%2Fspan%3E%3C%2Fscript%3E" data-mce-placeholder="1" width="20" height="20" alt="&lt;script&gt;"></div>
<h2>Software consulting</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-should-non-technical-founders-collaborate-with-software-developers/">(TechCrunch+) How should nontechnical founders collaborate with software developers?</a> As we mentioned in our last <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/experts-roundup-lead-magnets-e-commerce-trends-software-developer-qa/">roundup</a>, I interviewed the CEO of Wolfpack Digital, Georgina &#8220;Gina&#8221; Lupu Florian.</p>
<p><strong>Can you describe the intake process for new clients? How do you assess their requirements, and what information do you need before you can share timelines and budgets?</strong></p>
<p>The intake process can vary a lot depending on the particularities of each project and collaboration. We typically assess the information provided by our clients and put together a proposal that we refine afterwards with the client as we discover more about the product along the way.</p>
<p>To get to a robust estimated project timeline and budget, we consider user stories, wireframes, and/or a requirements document as the perfect starting point. We can either collect them directly from our clients (if they have them ready after attending incubators, etc.), or we can help with putting them together and join a discovery phase, which typically takes from a few hours to a few days. From the moment we have enough information to prepare a proposal, it usually takes less than a week to deliver it.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="u5ItGfYFeo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-should-non-technical-founders-collaborate-with-software-developers/">How should non technical founders collaborate with software developers?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How should non technical founders collaborate with software developers?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-should-non-technical-founders-collaborate-with-software-developers/embed/#?secret=FwxrKZx7Eb#?secret=u5ItGfYFeo" data-secret="u5ItGfYFeo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div style="width: 100%; height: 400px;" data-tf-widget="MXehi2kl"></div>
<p><script src="//embed.typeform.com/next/embed.js"></script></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/experts-weekly-microsegmentation-pmf-experiments-and-personalized-shopping/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2266696</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TechCrunch+ roundup: Stealth recruiting, virtual sales kickoffs, Google Cloud&#8217;s Q4</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/techcrunch-roundup-stealth-recruiting-virtual-sales-kickoffs-google-clouds-q4/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/techcrunch-roundup-stealth-recruiting-virtual-sales-kickoffs-google-clouds-q4/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 21:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online sellers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[special-purpose acquisition company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2266955</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“You’ve got to spend money to make money” is a cliché, but if you’re building a company that hopes to compete in the cloud, it’s just a fact.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Traditionally, companies hold in-person sales kickoffs (SKOs) in January and February to network, educate sales teams about new products and devise strategies for the year ahead.</p>
<p>These days, the convention centers and hotel ballrooms that once hosted those events are dark and quiet.</p>
<p>Even though most employees are vaccinated, companies are still reluctant to send them to in-person events, and in the midst of a pandemic, many workers are reluctant to get on a plane.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2266955" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><i>Full TechCrunch+ articles are only available to members<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">Use discount code <strong>TCPLUSROUNDUP</strong></a> to save 20% off a one- or two-year subscription</i></p>
<hr />
<p>One recent survey of sales and marketing professionals found that only half of respondents said they were likely to attend an event in H1 2022.</p>
<p>Hybrid events won&#8217;t give teams a chance to bond over karaoke, but with a tight agenda and a compelling theme, you can create a virtual or hybrid SKO that people will actually want to attend.</p>
<p>If you lead a sales team, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/how-to-organize-and-execute-an-effective-sales-kickoff-in-2022/">this post shares several strategies</a> for finding a theme that reflects your goals, as well as advice on scheduling, and tips on ways to express your company culture.</p>
<p>Even if your team is spread across several time zones, there&#8217;s still time to grab a sandwich and network: after all, Zoom karaoke still counts as team-building.</p>
<p>Thanks very much for reading TechCrunch+ this week!</p>
<p>Walter Thompson<br />
Senior Editor, TechCrunch+<br />
<a href="https://www.twitter.com/yourprotagonist">@yourprotagonist</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RoGtcwfTd2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/how-to-organize-and-execute-an-effective-sales-kickoff-in-2022/">How to organize and execute an effective hybrid sales kickoff event in 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to organize and execute an effective hybrid sales kickoff event in 2022&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/how-to-organize-and-execute-an-effective-sales-kickoff-in-2022/embed/#?secret=2tnfaOlNdP#?secret=RoGtcwfTd2" data-secret="RoGtcwfTd2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>With a $22B run rate, does it matter if Google Cloud is still losing money?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2153851" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153851" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2153851" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages-1173741201.jpg" alt="(GDD) China 2019 on September 10, 2019" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages-1173741201.jpg 4896w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages-1173741201.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages-1173741201.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages-1173741201.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages-1173741201.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages-1173741201.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages-1173741201.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages-1173741201.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2153851" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Lyu Liang/VCG via Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>“You’ve got to spend money to make money” is a cliché, but if you’re building a company that hopes to compete in the cloud, it’s a fact.</p>
<p>This week, Google Cloud reported $5.5 billion in revenue for Q4 2021, but “that was the good news,” reported Ron Miller and Alex Wilhelm.</p>
<p>“The bad news was that Google Cloud accrued operating losses worth $890 million at the same time.”</p>
<p>Given such high stakes, industry watchers don’t seem overly concerned by these ongoing losses, however.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Businesses of this nature require a lot of upfront investment and buildout of infrastructure and often don’t break even for several years,” said John Dinsdale, chief analyst at Synergy Research.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VuKKl11TIC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/02/with-a-22b-run-rate-does-it-matter-if-google-cloud-still-loses-money/">With a $22B run rate, does it matter if Google Cloud still loses money?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;With a $22B run rate, does it matter if Google Cloud still loses money?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/02/with-a-22b-run-rate-does-it-matter-if-google-cloud-still-loses-money/embed/#?secret=33VeBKsIqg#?secret=VuKKl11TIC" data-secret="VuKKl11TIC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>3 ways web3 recruiters can improve their hiring game</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2265569" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2265569" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2265569" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-172169766.jpg" alt="An arrow hitting the bullseye, slicing the earlier arrow in the centre." width="1024" height="717" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-172169766.jpg 1300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-172169766.jpg?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-172169766.jpg?resize=300,210 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-172169766.jpg?resize=768,538 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-172169766.jpg?resize=680,476 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-172169766.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2265569" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=motorenmano" target="_blank" rel="noopener">motorenmano <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>You wouldn’t hire a plumber to redo your wiring, and you shouldn’t hire a web3 developer if you’re building a team for your metaverse startup.</p>
<p>Investors are swooning over startups in these sectors, but a fat pre-seed check is not a hiring strategy.</p>
<p>Making matters more difficult, most developer talent is focused in a few verticals, and any offers you make must compare to incentives from companies like Apple and Microsoft.</p>
<p>“Engineers don’t want to only be putting out fires, they want to create and pioneer projects,” says Sergiu Matei, founder of remote talent platform Index.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2SAUg3zJow"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/02/3-ways-web3-recruiters-can-improve-their-hiring-game/">3 ways web3 recruiters can improve their hiring game</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 ways web3 recruiters can improve their hiring game&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/02/3-ways-web3-recruiters-can-improve-their-hiring-game/embed/#?secret=el14BpRpHB#?secret=2SAUg3zJow" data-secret="2SAUg3zJow" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Despite bumps, crypto investment starts 2022 with a roar</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996008" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996008" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996008" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996008" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The crypto market hasn’t had a good year so far, with Bitcoin losing nearly a fifth of its value, and other tokens seeing similar declines.</p>
<p>But VCs don’t seem to mind. In fact, funding for blockchain startups has already exceeded $4 billion so far in 2022, and investors seem intent on keeping up the pace, wrote Alex Wilhelm in The Exchange.</p>
<p>“Sure, SaaS valuations are coming back to Earth, and some investors are taking things a bit more slowly than before — at least so we’re told — but that newfound, or perhaps reforged, conservatism does not appear to be taking hold in the crypto market.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JIjyErJAEP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/01/despite-bumps-crypto-investment-starts-2022-with-a-roar/">Despite bumps, crypto investment starts 2022 with a roar</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Despite bumps, crypto investment starts 2022 with a roar&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/01/despite-bumps-crypto-investment-starts-2022-with-a-roar/embed/#?secret=5ymT8FwQFD#?secret=JIjyErJAEP" data-secret="JIjyErJAEP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Fintech outperformed the market in 2021, and it’s set to do even better</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2265177" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2265177" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2265177" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1247809421.jpg" alt="A Bank building with columns consisting of a digits matrix is shown on a laptop screen. Financial services available through the website on mobile devices" width="1024" height="580" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1247809421.jpg 2299w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1247809421.jpg?resize=150,85 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1247809421.jpg?resize=300,170 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1247809421.jpg?resize=768,435 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1247809421.jpg?resize=680,385 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1247809421.jpg?resize=1536,871 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1247809421.jpg?resize=2048,1161 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1247809421.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2265177" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=NatalyaBurova" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NatalyaBurova <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Public technology companies had a banner year in 2021, but fintech firms significantly outperformed the major stock indexes, according to a report by Matrix Partners.</p>
<p>Dana Stalder and Matt Brown from Matrix outlined the most interesting fintech trends of 2021 for TC+, and explained why they believe the sector will fare better than the broader market in 2022 as well.</p>
<p>“Fintech’s consistent outperformance signals that the changes brought about by COVID-19 – including shifts toward e-commerce, online payments and digital interactions over physical ones – are here to stay.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oNaNximJRR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/01/fintech-outperformed-the-market-in-2021-and-its-set-to-do-even-better/">Fintech outperformed the market in 2021, and it&#8217;s set to do even better</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fintech outperformed the market in 2021, and it&#8217;s set to do even better&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/01/fintech-outperformed-the-market-in-2021-and-its-set-to-do-even-better/embed/#?secret=Ict52xTHXn#?secret=oNaNximJRR" data-secret="oNaNximJRR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The MariaDB SPAC deal could prove to be a key test for unicorn exits</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996007" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996007" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996007" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996007" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>SPACs had a great run. But nothing lasts forever.</p>
<p>However, open source relational DB provider MariaDB’s SPAC deal may be a bellwether for startups too expensive to be sold, but not yet mature enough to IPO, wrote Alex Wilhelm in The Exchange.</p>
<p>“MariaDB is getting a pretty good price for its equity and a bundle of cash to boot. The transaction indicates that unicorns and companies near that valuation mark with mid-double-digit ARR can find a SPAC partner that will take them to the public markets far in advance of when they might be able to on their own.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YWwFS9Rc9K"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/02/the-mariadb-spac-deal-could-prove-to-be-a-key-test-for-unicorn-exits/">The MariaDB SPAC deal could prove to be a key test for unicorn exits</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The MariaDB SPAC deal could prove to be a key test for unicorn exits&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/02/the-mariadb-spac-deal-could-prove-to-be-a-key-test-for-unicorn-exits/embed/#?secret=VVzcvK9ZJz#?secret=YWwFS9Rc9K" data-secret="YWwFS9Rc9K" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>3 views: What does ‘Line Go Up’ tell us about the state of the NFT art market?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2265845" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2265845" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2265845" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1238043969.jpg" alt="An advertisement for Big Cats non-fungible token (NFT) on an electronic billboard in Times Square on Friday, Jan. 28, 2022." width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1238043969.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1238043969.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1238043969.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1238043969.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1238043969.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1238043969.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1238043969.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1238043969.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2265845" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=editorial&amp;photographer=Bloomberg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bloomberg <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Collectors spent $22 billion on NFTs in 2021, up from $100 million the year before.</p>
<p>Last month, Canadian videographer Dan Olson released a two-hour video about his strongly held views on web3 and blockchain technology titled “Line Goes Up — The Problem With NFTs.”</p>
<p>I asked John and Alex to share their thoughts on Olson’s video as a point of departure for discussing the state of the crypto industry in general. Here’s where we ended up:</p>
<ul>
<li>Walter Thompson: NFTs are scarcely minimum viable products</li>
<li>John Biggs: A shakeout has to happen for the tech to take off</li>
<li>Alex Wilhelm: I just don’t want your NFT</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QaIa9HRnnI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/02/3-views-what-does-line-go-up-tell-us-about-the-state-of-the-nft-art-market/">3 views: What does &#8216;Line Go Up&#8217; tell us about the state of the NFT art market?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 views: What does &#8216;Line Go Up&#8217; tell us about the state of the NFT art market?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/02/3-views-what-does-line-go-up-tell-us-about-the-state-of-the-nft-art-market/embed/#?secret=DumrSxBaG9#?secret=QaIa9HRnnI" data-secret="QaIa9HRnnI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>11 ways to make personalized shopping more effective and profitable</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2266528" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2266528" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2266528" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1288206657.jpg" alt="sign on the asphalt, yellow painted number eleven on grey street, yellow lines like a corner on the road, space for text" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1288206657.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1288206657.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1288206657.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1288206657.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1288206657.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/GettyImages-1288206657.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2266528" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Younes++Kraske+" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ounes Kraske <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>My favorite story from my time working in retail: helping a familiar customer find a book they were looking for, even though the only detail they could remember was that it had a blue cover.</p>
<p>I reflect on that moment whenever I consider how essential personalization is for online sellers. E-commerce platforms should use every signal they can detect to triangulate shoppers along the customer journey, writes Vitaly Alexandrov, founder and CEO of Food Rocket.</p>
<p>Alexandrov takes us on a deep dive of the online shopping space, sharing marketing tactics and data insights that make mundane shopping experiences more memorable.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is no longer a question of whether or not you should offer personalized digital experiences. Anything less is a death knell to your brand’s long-term success.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UCdIDDC335"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/11-ways-to-make-personalized-shopping-more-effective-and-profitable/">11 ways to make personalized shopping more effective and profitable</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;11 ways to make personalized shopping more effective and profitable&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/11-ways-to-make-personalized-shopping-more-effective-and-profitable/embed/#?secret=QbWF1EvcEN#?secret=UCdIDDC335" data-secret="UCdIDDC335" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>As public tech valuations fall, are startup investments evolving quickly enough?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996006" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996006" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996006" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996006" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>When a stock&#8217;s value falls 10% or more from its most recent high, it&#8217;s called a correction. This week, shares in Facebook, PayPal, Spotify, Snap and other high flyers saw double-digit percentage declines.</p>
<p>In yesterday&#8217;s edition of The Exchange, Alex Wilhelm looked at public tech valuations and concluded that the ground is shifting underfoot.</p>
<p>&#8220;Why? Investors had valued a host of companies like their pandemic bump was more akin to their new reality. However, it turns out that a lot of pandemic growth wasn’t free — it came at the expense of later growth.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zJVZMbM57J"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/as-public-tech-valuations-fall-are-startup-investments-evolving-quickly-enough/">As public tech valuations fall, are startup investments evolving quickly enough?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As public tech valuations fall, are startup investments evolving quickly enough?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/03/as-public-tech-valuations-fall-are-startup-investments-evolving-quickly-enough/embed/#?secret=nne8ByHaEz#?secret=zJVZMbM57J" data-secret="zJVZMbM57J" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/techcrunch-roundup-stealth-recruiting-virtual-sales-kickoffs-google-clouds-q4/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2266955</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After the acquisition: 3 startup executives share their exit experiences</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/after-the-acquisition-3-startup-founders-share-their-exit-experiences/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/after-the-acquisition-3-startup-founders-share-their-exit-experiences/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 21:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Acquia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cambium Learning Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital asset management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drupal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lexia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mailgun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mailjet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pathwire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pure Storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rackspace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rosetta stone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scott Dietzen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sinch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoma bravo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2266388</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In Part 1 of this series, we spoke to acquiring companies about the deal and how they integrate acquired firms. In Part 2, we talk to executives from the three companies that they bought.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In an interview at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/09/09/pure-storage-ceo-acquisitions-always-suck-worse-than-you-think/">TechCrunch Disrupt in 2014</a>, then-CEO of Pure Storage, Scott Dietzen, was asked about the possibility of exiting via acquisition.</p>
<p>He didn&#8217;t pull any punches: &#8220;Acquisitions always suck, and suck worse than you think that they are going to suck.&#8221;</p>
<p>That doesn&#8217;t sound like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/post-exit-blues-selling-a-startup-may-come-with-an-emotional-cost/">getting acquired</a> is the best thing that could happen to your startup, but this is only one perspective on the matter, and perhaps it depends <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/whether-to-sell-your-company-is-always-going-to-be-a-huge-decision-for-founders/">who you ask</a>.</p>
<p>If being acquired means losing the brand and identity you have worked so hard to build — or perhaps worse, losing your cultural identity — it probably will suck. If you get stuck with a company that simply imposes its will on you, it definitely will.</p>
<p>Sometimes, in spite of Dietzen&#8217;s proclamation, it can be at least OK, and both sides get something out of the deal: the acquiring company needs your product or your talent, you receive an exit and a check.</p>
<p>Previously, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/25/hard-cash-and-soft-skills-how-to-successfully-manage-an-acquisition/">we spoke to the acquiring companies to get their perspective</a> on the deal and how they fold these companies into the larger entity. Now, we&#8217;ll hear from executives who worked at three companies that they bought.</p>
<p>These companies said their acquisition experience was just fine, thank you very much. Though they aren&#8217;t about to talk crap about their new overlords, you do get the sense that they landed in a pretty decent spot, all things considered.</p>
<h2>Deciding to sell</h2>
<p>The companies we selected are not fresh startups by any means. One was owned by a private equity firm, and one was owned by another company when they were sold, so they had been around the block and knew what it was like to report to someone else. The last company, a 72-year-old operation, was the exception.</p>
<p>Will Conway, CEO of Pathwire, had been down this path before. His startup was a member of the YC Winter 2011 cohort, and was sold to Rackspace a year later. Private equity firm Thoma Bravo picked it up a while later and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/sinch-acquires-pathwire-the-company-behind-mailgun-and-mailjet-for-1-9b-to-add-email-into-its-api-based-communications-platform/">sold it to Sinch last year</a> for $1.9 billion.</p>
<p>As part of a private equity firm, Conway didn&#8217;t have a lot of input when it came to being sold. If the firm was going to sell, it was going to sell, but as Conway sees it, he landed with as good a company as he could have hoped for. Pathwire&#8217;s primary products, Mailgun and Mailjet, gave Sinch a missing email marketing piece, and fit nicely into the company&#8217;s platform of communications services.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/04/after-the-acquisition-3-startup-founders-share-their-exit-experiences/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2266388</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>